<iStressLess>

    <Content name="APP_NAME">PTSD Coach Australia</Content>

    <Content name="ROOT" ui="LayeredController">
        <Content name="firstLaunchSequence" ui="NavController" predicate="!dae.firstLaunch">
	        <Content name="EULA" displayName="License Agreement" ui="EULAController">
	            <![CDATA[
                    <h3>End User Licence Agreement for PTSD Coach Australia</h3>
                    <p>This is an End User Licence Agreement (this Agreement) between you and Commonwealth of Australia as represented by the Department of Veterans' Affairs (DVA) and the Department of Defence (DoD), and governs your use of the DVA and DoD PTSD mobile device application (the App). By installing and/or using the App, you agree to the terms of this agreement. Please read the terms and conditions carefully and in full prior to completing the installation process and using the App. If you do not agree with the terms and conditions please do not complete the installation or use the App.</p>
                    <h4>1. GENERAL USE</h4>
                    <h4>1.1 Installation and Use</h4>
                    <p>
                    DVA and DoD grant you a revokable, non-transferable, non-exclusive and limited licence (Licence) to install and use the App on your mobile device, running a validly licensed copy of the operating system for which the App was designed, for your personal use only, and strictly in accordance with the terms and conditions, commencing on the date that you download the App.
                    </p>
                    <h4>1.2 Updates </h4>
                    <p>
                    DVA and DoD are not required to provide updates or new releases pursuant to this agreement. DVA and DoD may change, add or remove any of the functionality of the App. These terms and conditions will govern any upgrade or supplement to the App unless we notify you of replacement terms in which case those terms will apply with respect to that upgrade or supplement. You should make sure that you regularly check for any updates to the Licensed Application that are available to download from the Google, or Apple app store. DVA and DoD may collect, share and use non-personal technical data and related information about your mobile device and the App to facilitate the provision of updates.  You agree that DVA and DoD can use this information as long as it does not personally identify you.</p>
                    <h4>2. PROHIBITIONS AND LIMITATIONS</h4>
                    <h4>2.1 Modifications</h4>
                    <p>
                    You shall not modify the whole or any part of the App or combine or incorporate the whole or any part of the App in any other program or system.
                    </p>
                    <h4>2.2 Reverse Engineering</h4>
                    <p>Subject to the Copyright Act 1968, you shall not reverse assemble or reverse compile the App or any part of the App.<p/>
                    <h4>2.3 Copying</h4>
                    <p>Subject to the Copyright Act 1968, you shall not copy the App, in whole or in part.</p>
                    <h4>2.4 Maintenance of Copyright Notices</h4>
                    <p>You must not remove or alter any copyright notices on any and all copies of the App.</p>
                    <h4>2.5 Commercial Use</h4>
                    <p>You may not use the App for commercial purposes, such as renting or leasing  the App.</p>
                    <h4>2.6 Compliance with Applicable Laws</h4>
                    <p>You must comply with all applicable laws regarding the use of the App.</p>
                    <h4>3. Ownership</h4>
                    <p>DVA and DoD retain ownership of the App whether in its original form or as modified by you during the term of the licence. All intellectual property rights in the App are retained by the Commonwealth of Australia (the Commonwealth). Nothing in this Agreement affects the ownership of moral rights in the App.</p>
                    <h4>4. TERMINATION</h4>
                    <p>
                    DVA and DoD may terminate this Agreement if you fail to comply with the terms and conditions of this Agreement. In such event, you must uninstall and otherwise remove all copies of the App in your possession. </p>
                    <h4>5. COPYRIGHT</h4>
                    <p>
                    The Commonwealth retains ownership of the App whether in its original form or as modified by you during the term of the licence. All intellectual property rights in the App (including text, graphics, logos, icons, images, music and audio clips, video clips, software, data compilations and any other form of information or content and design elements) are retained by the Commonwealth. Nothing in this agreement affects the ownership of moral rights in the App.</p>
                    <p>All rights not expressly granted are reserved by DVA and DoD.</p>
                    <h4>6. WARRANTIES</h4>
                    <p>DVA and DoD expressly disclaims any condition or warranty which would otherwise be implied in this Agreement. Where legislation implies in this agreement any condition or warranty, and that legislation avoids or prohibits provisions in a contract excluding or modifying application of or exercise or liability under such condition or warranty, the condition or warranty will be deemed to be included in this agreement.  DVA and DoD do not warrant or assume responsibility for the accuracy or completeness of any information, text, graphics or other items contained within the App. DVA and DoD make no warranties respecting any harm that may be caused by the App.</p>
                    <h4>7. INDEMNITY AND LIABILITY</h4>
                    <p>You agree to indemnify DVA and DoD, their personnel and subcontractors from any loss (including reasonable legal costs and expenses), or liability for any loss or damage arising out of your use of or inability to use the App or with respect to the material provided in the App or any part thereof, including but not limited to errors or omissions contained therein. </p>
                    <h4>8. Confidentiality </h4>
                    <p>Personal information you enter in this App is stored in your device and will not be accessed or used by DVA and DoD.  It is your responsibility to ensure your device is held in a secure, private place, to prevent others viewing the personal details stored with this App. This clause will survive the termination of this Agreement.</p>
                    <h4>9. Disclaimer</h4>
                    <p>The information on this App is intended as a general reference only. DVA and DoD make information available on the understanding that the Commonwealth is not thereby engaged in rendering professional advice. You must not rely upon the material provided on this App as a statement of advice or Government policy on any particular matter. DVA and DoD make every reasonable effort to maintain current and accurate information. You are responsible for making your own assessment as to the accuracy, currency, completeness and relevance of this information for their purposes before relying on the material in any important matter. Users should always obtain any appropriate professional advice relevant to their particular circumstances. The material provided in the App may include the views or recommendations of third parties and does not necessarily reflect the views of the Australian Government or indicate a commitment to a particular decision, policy or course of action.</p>
                    <p>DVA and DoD encourage you to check with us if you have any concerns about the information on this App.</p>
                    <h4>10. External Links </h4>
                    <p>This App may include links to third party websites. Links to other sites are provided for your convenience. DVA and DoD do not accept responsibility for the accuracy or completeness of information on any third party websites. In some cases the material may incorporate or summarise views, standards or recommendations of third parties. Such material is assembled in good faith, but does not necessarily reflect the considered views of the Commonwealth, or indicate a commitment to a particular course of action.</p>
                    <h4>11. Law</h4>
                    <p>This Agreement shall be governed by and construed in accordance with the laws for the time being in force in the Australian Capital Territory, Australia and the parties agree to submit to the jurisdiction of the courts and tribunals of that State.</p>
                    <h4>12. Severability</h4>
                    <p>Should any part of this Agreement be or become invalid, that part shall be severed from this Agreement. Such invalidity shall not affect the validity of the remaining provisions of the Agreement.</p>
                    <h4>13. Entire agreement</h4>
                    <p>This Agreement supersedes all prior agreements, arrangements and undertakings between the parties and constitutes the entire agreement between the parties relating to the App. No addition to or modification of any provision of this Agreement shall be binding upon the parties unless made by written instrument signed by both parties.</p>
	            ]]>
	            <Content name="@button" displayName="Tap to Accept" title="Welcome!">
	                <![CDATA[
	                <p>
	                Welcome to <b>PTSD Assist Australia</b>! This app was developed for trauma survivors. Whether you have Posttraumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD), or you are concerned that you might, this app is for you. This app won't diagnose you with PTSD or offer you treatment - only a trained mental health provider can do that. But it can help you learn about PTSD, and it will give you tools for managing the stresses that can follow a trauma. This app is based on the current evidence-based understandings of PTSD.
	                </p>
	                <p>
	               To get the most out of this app, you should set some things up as soon as possible. You will need to select:
                    </p>
	                <ul>
	                <li>Whether you are a currently serving ADF member (including family member); or a former serving member (including family member), this will ensure the app provides you with the most relevant information about support available,</li>
	                <li>Friends, loved ones, and/or professionals who can help when you're feeling stressed,</li>
	                <li>Pictures on your phone that you find comforting or fun, and</li>
	                <li>Songs on your phone that you find relaxing or put you in a good mood.</li>
	                </ul>
	                <p>
	               You can change your selections at any time by visiting Setup.
	                </p>
	                <p>
	               To do this now, tap "Continue with Setup." Otherwise, tap "Skip Setup."  If you skip Setup, tools in the app that use these items will not be available until you complete Setup.  
	                </p>
	                ]]>
	                <Content name="@button" displayName="Skip Setup" ref="home"/>
	                <Content name="@button" displayName="Continue with Setup" ref="setup"/>
	            </Content>
	        </Content>
        </Content>
        <Content name="setupSequence" layerStyle="modal" ui="NavController">
	        <Content name="setup" backButton="Setup" displayName="Setup" title="Setup" ui="ContentViewController">
	            <Content name="@inline"><![CDATA[
	                Personalise this app.  I am a:
	            ]]></Content>
	            <Content name="@inline" ui="PickListController" settingKey="userType">
	                <Content name="serving" displayName="I am a Serving Member (or Family)"/>
	                <Content name="exserving" displayName="I am an ex-Serving Member (or Family)"/>
	            </Content>
                <Content name="@inline" >Tap to select images that are soothing to you. These will become useful in subsequent parts of the app.</Content>
	            <Content name="@inline" ui="ContentListViewController">
	                <Content displayName="Choose Images" title="Soothing Images" backButton="Images" ui="ChosenImagesViewController" editing="true">
	                    <Content name="@add" displayName="Choose Images" title="Choose Images" ui="ImagesPickerViewController"/>
	                </Content>
                </Content>
                <Content name="@inline" >Tap to select audio that you find calming. Selected tracks will become useful in subsequent parts of the app.</Content>
                <Content name="@inline" ui="ContentListViewController">
	                <Content displayName="Choose Songs or Audio" title="Soothing Audio" backButton="Audio" ui="ChosenAudioListViewController" editing="true"/>
                </Content>
                <Content name="@inline" >Select support contacts that you could call upon in times of hardship or need.</Content>
                <Content name="@inline" ui="ContentListViewController">
	                <Content name="setupContacts" displayName="Choose Support Contacts" title="Support Contacts" backButton="Support Contacts" ui="ChosenContactListViewController" editing="true"
	                    selectionIcon_file="physician.png" selectionIconEmpty_file="physician_hole.png">
	                    Add your support contacts here.  You can also tap the icon to the right of one contact to indicate that this contact is your preferred mental health professional.
	                </Content>
	            </Content>
	            <Content name="@back" icon="home_icon.png" ref="home"/>
	            <Content name="@button" displayName="Continue" ref="home"/>
	            <Content name="@help" icon="help_icon.png" displayName="Setup Help" ui="ContentViewController"><![CDATA[
	                <p>
					In order to get the most out of this app, you should select some items that you already have on your device that you find soothing or pleasant. These items will be provided to you when you are in need of tools to manage your distress. 
	                </p>
	                <p>
					You will need to select:
                    </p>
					<ul>
					<li>Whether you are a serving ADF member or an ex-ADF member</li>
	                <li>Friends, loved ones, or providers from your contact list that can help you when you are feeling stressed (including your primary mental health care provider in case you choose to share information from this app with them to assist in your care)</li>
	                <li>Pictures on your phone that you find comforting or funny</li>
	                <li>Songs on your phone that you find soothing or that remind you of happy times</li>
					</ul>
	                <p>
					You can change your selections at any time by visiting Setup.
	                </p>
	            ]]></Content>
	        </Content>
	    </Content>
        
        <Content name="homeSequence" ui="NavController">
	        <Content name="home" displayName="PTSD Coach Australia" backButton="Home" ui="PaneledController">
	            <Content name="homeGridPane" buttonTheme="theme_big_button" ui="HomeController" 
	                buttongrid_cellsPerRow="1" buttongrid_buttonjust="left" >
	                <Content displayName="Learn" icon="learn_about.png" ref="learn"/>
	                <Content displayName="Self Assessment" icon="self_assess.png" ref="assess"/>
	                <Content displayName="Manage Symptoms" icon="manage.png" ref="manage"/>
	                <Content displayName="Find Support" icon="find_support.png" ref="support"/>
	                <Content displayName="Schedule Reminders" icon="schedule_reminders.png" ref="schedule"/>
	            </Content>
	            <Content name="reminderPane" icon="117-todo.png" displayName="Due Reminders" ui="ReminderListController" dueOnly="true">
	            </Content>
	            <Content name="@left" displayName="Setup" icon="settings_icon.png" ref="setup"/>
	            <Content name="@help" displayName="Help" icon="help_icon.png" title="PTSD Coach Help" ui="ContentViewController">
	            	<Content name="@inline" predicate="dae.platform=='android'">
	                <![CDATA[
	                    <table>
	                    <tr><td colspan="2">
	                    <h3 style="padding-top:10px;margin-bottom:4px;"><a href="content:///about">About</a></h3>
	                    </td></tr>
	                    <tr><td colspan="2">
	                    <hr/>
	                    <h3 style="margin-bottom:0px;">Learn about PTSD</h3>
	                    </td></tr>
	                    <tr><td valign="top">
	                    <img src="Content/learn_about.png" height="100" width="100"/>
	                    </td><td valign="top">
	                    This section of the app contains information about PTSD and how to go about getting help.  Understanding what is going on for you, and knowing how treatments and supports work is an important part of tackling PTSD.
	                    </td></tr>
	                    <tr><td colspan="2">

	                    <hr/>
	                    <h3 style="margin-bottom:0px;">Take Assessment</h3>
	                    </td></tr>
	                    <tr><td valign="top">
	                    <img src="Content/self_assess.png" height="100" width="100"/>
	                    </td><td valign="top">
	                    Here you can do an assessment to measure how your PTSD symptoms are tracking.  This app can't tell you if you have PTSD -- only a mental health provider can do that. The Take Assessment section can help identify how severe your symptoms are, and the Track History section can help you see if you are getting better or worse over time.  You can also email the results of your assessment to your chosen health provider.
	                    </td></tr>
	                    <tr><td colspan="2">

	                    <hr/>
	                    <h3 style="margin-bottom:0px;">Manage Symptoms</h3>
	                    </td></tr>
	                    <tr><td valign="top">
	                    <img src="Content/manage.png" height="100" width="100"/>
	                    </td><td valign="top">
	                    Here you can find tools to help you manage your symptoms. There are a lot of different tools in this app, and it's a good idea to experiment to see what works best for you. You can let the app select a tool based on how you are feeling (by using the Symptoms tab), or if you have a favorite tool, you can jump straight to it using the Tools tab.
	                    </td></tr>
	                    <tr><td colspan="2">

	                    <hr/>
	                    <h3 style="margin-bottom:0px;">Find Support</h3>
	                    </td></tr>
	                    <tr><td valign="top">
	                    <img src="Content/find_support.png" height="100" width="100"/>
	                    </td><td valign="top">
	                   This part of the app has resources for finding help.  Whether you would like to talk to someone straight away, or find a mental health provider you can work with, this part of the app has relevant information, contact numbers and web links.
	                    </td></tr>
	                    <tr><td colspan="2">

	                    <hr/>
	                    <h3 style="margin-bottom:0px;">Schedule Reminders</h3>
	                    </td></tr>
	                    <tr><td valign="top">
	                    <img src="Content/schedule_reminders.png" height="100" width="100"/>
	                    </td><td valign="top">
	                    Here you will find a reminder function that can help you manage your PTSD. You can schedule reminders to take the assessment in this app or to use one of the app's tools.  In fact, you can add reminders for any important event or appointment. This part of the app can help you organise all the activities that are important to you in managing your health.    
	                    </td></tr>
	                    </table>
	                ]]>
	            	</Content>
	            	<Content name="@inline" predicate="dae.platform=='iphone'" html="true">
	                <![CDATA[
	                    <link rel="stylesheet" href="stylesheets/iphone.css" />
	                    <ul>
	                    <li id="foo" class="arrow">
	                    <a href="content:///about">About</a></li>
	                    </ul>
	                    <script>
	                    document.getElementById("foo").addEventListener('touchstart', function(event) {
	                    //event.preventDefault();
	                    this.style.background = '#88F url(../images/chevron.png) no-repeat right center';
	                    }, false);
	                    document.getElementById("foo").addEventListener('touchend', function(event) {
	                    //event.preventDefault();
	                    this.style.background = 'transparent url(../images/chevron.png) no-repeat right center';
	                    }, false);
	                    </script>
	                    <ul ><li>
	                    <table>
	                    <tr>
	                    <td>
	                    <h3>Learn about PTSD</h3>
	                    This section of the app contains information about PTSD and how to go about getting help.  Understanding what is going on for you, and knowing how treatments and supports work is an important part of tackling PTSD.
	                    </td>
	                    <td>
	                    <img src="Content/learn_about.png" height="100" width="100"/>
	                    </td>
	                    </tr>
	                    </table>
	                    </li><li>
	                    <table>
	                    <tr>
	                    <td>
	                    <h3>Take Assessment</h3>
	                    Here you can do an assessment to measure how your PTSD symptoms are tracking.  This app can't tell you if you have PTSD -- only a mental health provider can do that. The Take Assessment section can help identify how severe your symptoms are, and the Track History section can help you see if you are getting better or worse over time.  You can also email the results of your assessment to your chosen health provider.
	                    </td>
	                    <td>
	                    <img src="Content/self_assess.png" height="100" width="100"/>
	                    </td>
	                    </tr>
	                    </table>
	                    </li><li>
	                    <table>
	                    <tr>
	                    <td>
	                    <h3>Manage Symptoms</h3>
	                    Here you can find tools to help you manage your symptoms. There are a lot of different tools in this app, and it's a good idea to experiment to see what works best for you. You can let the app select a tool based on how you are feeling (by using the Symptoms tab), or if you have a favorite tool, you can jump straight to it using the Tools tab.
	                    </td>
	                    <td>
	                    <img src="Content/manage.png" height="100" width="100"/>
	                    </td>
	                    </tr>
	                    </table>
	                    </li><li>
	                    <table>
	                    <tr>
	                    <td>
	                    <h3>Find Support</h3>
                        This part of the app has resources for finding help.  Whether you would like to talk to someone straight away, or find a mental health provider you can work with, this part of the app has relevant information, contact numbers and web links.
	                    </td>
	                    <td>
	                    <img src="Content/find_support.png" height="100" width="100"/>
	                    </td>
	                    </tr>
	                    </table>
	                    </li><li>
	                    <table>
	                    <tr>
	                    <td>
	                    <h3>Schedule Reminders</h3>
	                    Here you will find a reminder function that can help you manage your PTSD. You can schedule reminders to take the assessment in this app or to use one of the app's tools.  In fact, you can add reminders for any important event or appointment. This part of the app can help you organise all the activities that are important to you in managing your health.
	                    </td>
	                    <td>
	                    <img src="Content/schedule_reminders.png" height="100" width="100"/>
	                    </td>
	                    </tr>
	                    </table>
	                    </li></ul>
	                ]]></Content>
	                <Content name="about" displayName="About" title="PTSD Coach Australia" ui="ContentViewController" html="true"><![CDATA[
	                    <div style="width:100%;text-align:center;">
	                    <img src="Content/ptsdcoach_australia_logo.png" width="200" height="200" style="text-align:center;"/>
	                    </div>
	                    <p>
	                    <b>PTSD Coach</b> is a mobile phone application for people with Posttraumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD) and those interested in learning more about PTSD.
	                    </p>
	                    <p>
	                    This application provides:
                        </p>
	                    <ul>
	                    <li>Education about PTSD</li>
	                    <li>A self-assessment</li>
	                    <li>Tools for managing distress associated with Posttraumatic Stress</li>
	                    <li>A direct connection to crisis support</li>
	                    <li>Information about professional treatment</li>
	                    </ul>
	                    <p>
	                    It can be used as a stand-alone education and symptom management tool, or to augment face-to-face care with a mental health provider.
	                    </p>
	                    <img src="Content/dva-logo.png" width="130" height="130" style="float:right;margin:10px;"/>
	                    <p>
	                    PTSD Coach has been adapted for Australian users by the Australian Centre for Posttraumatic Mental Health, for the Department of Veterans' Affairs and the Department of Defence.
	                    </p>
	                    <p>
	                    This app is based on the U.S. PTSD Coach app, which was a collaborative effort between the VA's National Center for PTSD and the DoD's National Center for Telehealth and Technology.
	                    </p>
	                    <p>
	                    U.S. PTSD Coach Project Team:
                        </p>
	                    <ul>
	                    <li>Julia E. Hoffman, Psy.D.</li>
	                    <li>Laura H. Wald, Ph.D.</li>
	                    <li>Eric Kuhn, Ph.D.</li>
	                    <li>Carolyn Greene, Ph.D.</li>
	                    <li>Josef I. Ruzek, Ph.D.</li>
	                    <li>Kenneth Weingardt, Ph.D.</li>
	                    </ul>
	                ]]></Content>
	            </Content>
	        </Content>
        </Content>
	        
        <Content name="tabs" ui="TabController">
	        <Content name="@back" icon="home_icon.png" ref="home"/>
            <Content ui="NavController" displayName="Learn" icon="84-lightbulb.png">
	            <Content displayName="Learn" name="learn" buttonTheme="theme_big_button" backButton="Learn" ui="ButtonGridController"
	                buttongrid_cellsPerRow="1" buttongrid_buttonjust="left">
                    <Content name="@back" icon="home_icon.png" ref="home"/>
	                <Content name="learnPTSD" displayName="Learn about PTSD" title="Learn about PTSD" icon="learn_PTSD.png" backButton="Topics" ui="ContentListViewController" child_ui="ContentViewController">
	                    <Content displayName="What is PTSD?" fixedButtons="true" title="What is PTSD?" audio="001 What is PTSD MST.mp3"><![CDATA[
                            <p>
	                        <b>Posttraumatic Stress Disorder</b> (or <b>PTSD</b>) is a psychological disorder that can arise following exposure to traumatic events. These events include things like combat, disasters, terrorism, serious accidents, or physical and sexual assault. PTSD involves a range of symptoms
                            </p>
	                        <ul>
	                            <li>Re-experiencing or reliving the trauma, such as having flashbacks, nightmares, or becoming very upset when reminded of the trauma.</li>
	                            <li>Avoiding or staying away from places or people because they remind you of the trauma, cutting yourself off from others, and/or feeling emotionally flat or numb.</li>
	                            <li>Increased arousal - such as feeling on guard, being irritable, trouble sleeping or startling easily.</li>
	                        </ul>
                            <p>The symptoms of PTSD can lead to problems in functioning in social settings, family life, at work.</p>
	                    ]]></Content>
	                    <Content displayName="How PTSD develops" fixedButtons="true" title="How PTSD develops" audio="002 How PTSD Develops 2.mp3"><![CDATA[
	                        After a trauma, it's not unusual to have distressing memories and to become upset when reminded of what happened.  Trauma can affect how people think about themselves, about others, the world, and the future.  For most, these reactions lessen over time and thinking returns to normal. For some, reactions continue and may be severe enough to disrupt day to day life.  How people respond to these early, normal reactions, in part, can determine if PTSD develops.  For example, because memories and reminders of the trauma are distressing, it makes sense to want to avoid them.  However, too much avoidance can prevent a person from adequately dealing with the memories and reminders and making sense of what happened.  This may mean normal trauma reactions become more lasting PTSD symptoms. 
	                    ]]></Content>
	                    <Content displayName="How common is PTSD?" fixedButtons="true" title="How common is PTSD?" audio="003 How Common Is PTSD MST.mp3"><![CDATA[
	                        Although most people recover after a trauma, it is not uncommon for people to develop PTSD.  About 5% of the general Australian population will have PTSD in their lifetime, with women being more than twice as likely to develop it than men.  Following a trauma, it can be expected that around 20% of women and 8% of men will develop PTSD.  Certain types of trauma, such as rape and combat, can cause even higher rates.  Between 5 and 20% of Australian veterans will experience PTSD.  Defence research indicates that about 8% of ADF personnel have developed PTSD. 
	                    ]]></Content>
	                    <Content displayName="Who develops PTSD?" fixedButtons="true" title="Who develops PTSD?" audio="004 Who Develops PTSD 2.mp3"><![CDATA[
	                        <p>
	                        Developing PTSD is not a sign of weakness. It can happen to anyone exposed to trauma. However, there are some factors that can make it more likely.  These include having a prior trauma, having been abused as a child, having a pre-existing mental health problem, a family history of mental illness and/or being female. 
	                        </p>
	                        <p>
	                        Reactions <b>during</b> trauma can increase your risk. Extreme reactions are signs that the event was especially traumatic - these might include on the one hand feeling numb or detached from yourself or your surroundings or on the other hand experiencing intense and prolonged anxiety, including a panic attack.  Being seriously injured also puts one at higher risk.  
	                        </p>
	                        <p>
	                        Risk factors <b>after</b> trauma include lack of social support and experiencing additional life stressors (e.g., job loss, divorce). 
	                        </p>
	                    ]]></Content>
	                    <Content displayName="How long does PTSD last?" fixedButtons="true" title="How long does PTSD last?" audio="005 How long does PTSD Last 2.mp3"><![CDATA[
	                        PTSD symptoms usually appear very soon after trauma.  For most people, these symptoms go away on their own within the weeks and months after the trauma.  Some symptoms can last for many years.  PTSD symptoms can stay at a fairly constant level of severity or individuals can have periods when symptoms are not very intense and other times when symptoms are severe.  PTSD symptoms can worsen during times of stress or when trauma survivors are reminded of the trauma (e.g. anniversaries).  How long PTSD lasts also depends on whether effective treatment is received.
	                    ]]></Content>
	                    <Content displayName="Related problems" fixedButtons="true" title="Related problems" audio="006 Related Problems MST.mp3"><![CDATA[
	                        Other problems also commonly occur alongside PTSD.  These include depression, other anxiety disorders, anger, and alcohol and substance use problems.  In fact, more than half of men with PTSD have alcohol problems and nearly half of women with PTSD have depression.  PTSD also can reduce one's ability to function in relationships, at work and study, and in leisure activities.  In addition, people with PTSD may suffer physical symptoms and may be at increased risk of medical problems.
	                    ]]></Content>
	                    <Content displayName="PTSD treatment" fixedButtons="true" title="PTSD treatment" audio="007 PTSD Treatment 2.mp3"><![CDATA[
	                        <p>
	                       PTSD is treated with counselling or medication, or a combination of these.  The most effective treatments for PTSD are exposure-based cognitive-behavioural therapies (CBT).  These treatments involve exploring how the trauma has negatively affected one's thinking and behaviour and helping survivors respond in more adaptive ways to what happened and what it might mean. Treatment may also include helping the trauma survivor really focus (safely, and with support) on the distressing trauma memories and reminders that they've been avoiding, learning that they can survive them and be ok.  Individuals are also taught coping skills to more effectively deal with stress and manage PTSD symptoms, much like the skills available on this app.
	                        </p>
	                        <p>
	                        For more information about treatment, including where to find it, see the Find Support section of this app (see the Find Support Tab for links)
	                        </p>
	                    ]]></Content>
	                    <Content displayName="Do I have PTSD?" fixedButtons="true" title="Do I have PTSD?" audio="008 Do I have PTSD 2.mp3"><![CDATA[
	                        <p>
	                       Only a trained mental health provider can determine if you have PTSD.  However, there are self-tests, including the one on this app, which can help you decide if your symptoms require a more thorough evaluation from a health provider.  If you suspect that you have PTSD, talk with your doctor about a referral to a mental health provider.  Also, it is important to remember that some people may develop other conditions, such as depression, after experiencing a trauma. 
	                        </p>
	                        <p>
	                       If your trauma was less than a fortnight ago and you are not in too much distress or having problems functioning with work, relationships or study, then you may just want to watch and wait to see if your symptoms get better on their own.  Using the tools in this app can help. However if your symptoms are very distressing or if you do not seem to be getting better after a couple of weeks, seek professional help.  
	                        </p>
	                        <p>
	                        To take the self-assessment now, click on Assess at the bottom of the screen.
	                        </p>
	                    ]]></Content>
	                    <Content displayName="I have PTSD..." fixedButtons="true" title="I have PTSD..." audio="009 I have PTSD 2.mp3"><![CDATA[
	                        <p>
	                       If you've been diagnosed with PTSD, the tools on this app may help you better manage your symptoms.  However, this app is not intended or designed as a replacement for psychological treatment from a mental health provider.  If you are currently in treatment for PTSD, it's important to talk with your mental health provider about using this app. Individuals with PTSD often find that having multiple tools and sources of support is a great strategy for successfully dealing with PTSD symptoms.  Your mental health provider can access handy guides to integrating this app into your treatment. See the Find Support tab for links to these resources at the Department of Veterans' Affairs At Ease website.
	                        </p>
	                        <p>
	                        Remember: effective treatment for PTSD is available! You don't have to live with your symptoms forever.
	                        </p>
	                    ]]></Content>
	                </Content>
	                <Content displayName="Learn About Professional Care" icon="prof_care.png" backButton="Topics" title="Professional Care"
	                    ui="ContentListViewController" tableTheme="theme_list_smaller" child_ui="ContentViewController"
	                    cellHeight="50" cellLines="2">
	                    <Content displayName="Do I need professional help?" fixedButtons="true" title="Do I need professional help?" audio="010 Do I Need Professional Help 2.mp3"><![CDATA[
                            <p>
	                        Whether or not you need help can only be determined by you and a trained mental health provider. However, you can do the self-assessment on this app to see if you are scoring in the high, medium, or low range of symptoms. You can also ask yourself these questions. If you answer yes to any of them, then you might want to seek help.
                            </p>
	                        <ul>
	                        <li>Have you felt sad or depressed most of the time for longer than two weeks?</li>
	                        <li>Have you been feeling anxious or had distressing thoughts almost all the time?</li>
	                        <li>Have you had trouble working or meeting your daily responsibilities? </li>
	                        <li>Have you had problems in your relationships, or trouble taking care of your family?</li>
	                        <li>Have you increased your use of alcohol, illicit drugs, or prescription medications, or have you been using them to cope with your problems lately?</li>
	                        <li>Are you very angry most of the time?</li>
	                        <li>Do other people say they worry about you and think you should go talk to someone?</li>
	                        <li>Are you having trouble sleeping most of the time?</li>
	                        <li>Are you having trouble eating, or have you gained or lost a lot of weight without trying?</li>
	                        <li>Are you thinking about committing suicide, hurting, or killing someone else?</li>
	                        </ul>
	                        <p>
	                       If you said yes to this last one, please call 000 or go immediately to the nearest hospital emergency department. 
	                        </p>
	                        <p>
	                       If you said yes to any of the others, you would likely benefit from talking with a mental health provider. Ex-serving members can see your GP, or can call the VVCS - Veterans and Veterans Families Counselling Service, 24 hours a day on <a href="tel:1800-011-046">1800-011-046</a>. Current ADF personnel can contact their Garrison Health Service 24 hours a day on  <a href="tel:1800-467-425">1800-467-425</a>. You don't have to wait for an emergency to speak to someone.
	                        </p>
	                    ]]></Content>
	                    <Content displayName="Why do people usually seek professional help?" fixedButtons="true" title="Why do people usually seek professional help?" audio="011 Why Do People usually Seek Professional Help 2.mp3"><![CDATA[
                            <p>
                           Seeking help is a sign of strength, not weakness. Talking to a counsellor can improve your ability to help yourself. 
                            </p>
	                        <p>
	                        The first few weeks after a traumatic event can be hard. It is common to have trouble with life, avoid situations, feel very nervous, and have trouble sleeping. But if you don't get better in the first month, then you should think about seeking help.  One of the most helpful ways to feel better and get back on track is to work with a mental health provider.  Health providers who specialise in working with PTSD can help you learn to manage your feelings and thoughts. They can also help you feel more relaxed about connecting with people in your daily life, pursuing your goals, and focusing on your future.  Your GP is generally the best place to start.  Current ADF personnel can self-refer to their local Mental Health and Psychology Sections or a Medical Officer.
	                        </p>
	                       
	                    ]]></Content>
	                    <Content displayName="Will it really work?" fixedButtons="true" title="Will it really work?" audio="012 Will it really Work 2.mp3"><![CDATA[
	                        <p>
	                        Scientific evidence shows that many types of therapy and medications really are effective.
	                        </p>
	                        <p>
	                        It may be hard to imagine now, but you can work through your stress.  Counselling may also help ease your transition back home or into civilian life. 
	                        </p>
	                        <p>
	                        Worried that counsellors won't be able to help you or won't understand what you have been through?  You may be surprised to find out that they can help, and will work hard to understand you and your experiences. Counsellors are highly trained mental health providers. Some, like the VVCS, specialise in working with military personnel and veterans. 
	                        </p>
	                        <p>
	                        If you have a few sessions with a counsellor and you don't think it's going well, you can talk to the counsellor or your GP about what you want changed or you can ask for a different counsellor.  Counsellors are focused on your recovery and will help you get the care you need. 
	                        </p>
	                        ]]></Content>
	                    <Content displayName="PTSD Treatments That Work" fixedButtons="true" title="PTSD Treatments That Work" audio="013 PTSD Treatments that Work MST.mp3"><![CDATA[
	                        <p>
	                        The good news is that there are several types of treatment which work for PTSD.
	                        </p>
	                        <p>
	                        The best evidence supports Trauma-Focused Cognitive Behavioral Therapy (TF-CBT) for PTSD. Two types of CBT that have the most research behind them are Prolonged Exposure Therapy and Cognitive Processing Therapy.
	                        </p>
	                        <p>
	                       Research also supports the use of Eye Movement Desensitisation and Reprocessing, or EMDR, and finally, medications called Selective Serotonin Reuptake Inhibitors, or SSRIs.
	                        </p>
	                        <p>
	                        If you have PTSD, you can look for a counsellor who uses one of these approaches. Within the Defence or DVA health care systems, many mental health providers are trained in providing these evidence based treatments.
	                        </p>
	                    ]]></Content>
	                    <Content displayName="How about things like scheduling, cost, and transportation?" fixedButtons="true" title="How about things like scheduling, cost, and transportation?" audio="014 What Abou Practical Things 2.mp3"><![CDATA[
	                        <p>
	                        When considering professional counselling, many people worry about practical things that may keep them from getting help. Concerns about how to find a counsellor, the cost of treatment, getting time off from work, and transport to appointments are very common. Each is addressed briefly below.
	                        </p>
	                        <p>
	                        <b>Finding a counsellor:</b> A good place to start is to ask your GP for a referral.  If you are a veteran or the partner of a veteran, you can also call the VVCS - Veterans and Veterans Families Counselling Service to find a local mental health provider with experience working with veterans. You can call  <a href="tel:1800-011-046">1800-011-046</a> 24 hours a day. You can also check out the Find Support tab to find web links to resources for counselling and support. If you are an ADF member your closest Garrison Health Service can assist you with referral to mental health provider.
	                        </p>
	                        <p>
	                        <b>Cost:</b> You may be able to access mental health care at no cost. For serving Defence members, free access to treatment and support is available via Garrison Health Services, and via referral to the VVCS - Veterans and Veterans Families Counselling Service. For eligible ex-serving members, DVA pays for treatment for those with a diagnosis of PTSD. Access to individual and group based treatment at no cost for you and your family may also be available through the VVCS - Veterans and Veterans Families Counselling Service. Call the VVCS 24 hours a day, on <a href="tel:1800-011-046">1800-011-046</a>. Alternatively, opportunities to access subsidised counselling under the Medicare system can be discussed with your GP.
	                        </p>
	                        <p>
	                        <b>Time off from work:</b> If you need flexible appointments so you do not miss work, look for a counsellor that will work with your schedule. You need to find a good time where you won't feel rushed. Most employers will understand and help you take care of your health, whether it's physical or emotional. Often, people work out a flexible schedule with their boss to free up time for their appointment. 
	                        </p>
	                        <p>
	                        <b>Transportation:</b> Some people have problems getting to and from appointments. Ex-serving members may be eligible to access transport assistance through DVA. If this is not available to you, public transport may be an option or getting a lift with someone. Maybe you could arrange to borrow a vehicle. Consider all your options. You might be surprised at how many people will take the time to help you get to an appointment.
	                    	</p>
	                    ]]></Content>
	                    <Content displayName="What does it mean about me if I ask for help?" fixedButtons="true" title="What does it mean about me if I ask for help?" audio="015 What does it say about me if I ask for Help 2.mp3"><![CDATA[
	                        <p>
	                        Remember: no one is alone in this world. People are here to help. Perhaps you believe that you should be able to handle your problems without help from others. But, people who use the sources of help around them are able to cope better than those who choose not to.  Trying to cope on your own often makes things harder than needed. It can also add loneliness and isolation to your problems.
	                        </p>
	                        <p>
	                       You may think that needing help means that you're not normal. You may also believe that seeking help means that you are not fit to do normal things. It is common to have problems. Many people report some type of concern about their mental health after stressful experiences.
	                        </p>
	                        <p>
	                        Don't feel guilty about taking time to get yourself well. You will be better able to live a fulfilling life if you are feeling better.
	                        </p>
	                        <p>
	                        Talking about your experiences helps you feel more in control. Getting the support you need to live your life more fully shows strength, self-respect and courage.
	                        </p>
	                    ]]></Content>
	                    <Content displayName="What if I am embarrassed about seeking help?" fixedButtons="true" title="What if I am embarrassed about seeking help?" audio="016 What if I'm embarrassed about seeking help.mp3"><![CDATA[
	                        <p>
	                        You don't have to tell people that you're working with a counsellor. You can just say you have an appointment and that it's personal.  
	                        </p>
	                        <p>
	                        Try not to be upset with friends or family that worry about you. Take it as a sign that they care and want the best for you and are probably looking for ways to help.
	                        </p>
	                        <p>
	                        You may think that people will make fun of you for getting help, because at one point you may have overheard someone making fun of someone in your situation.  But you will come to find out that this usually isn't true. Many men and women who served in the military have reported some concern about their mental health. 
	                        </p>
	                        <p>
	                        Expecting embarrassment and shame for asking for help is one of the main reasons why people don't seek help. You might ask yourself the following question:  Is it more important for me to worry about what someone else thinks of me? Or, is it important to get the help I need to move on with my life? 
							</p>
	                    ]]></Content>
	                    <Content displayName="Who can help me?" fixedButtons="true" title="Who can help me?" audio="017 Who Can Help me 2.mp3" ><![CDATA[
	                        <p>
	                       As you think about getting care, know that there are many experts to help you. In this section, you can read about the roles and duties of GP's, Mental Health Social Workers, Psychologists, Psychiatrists, and Pastoral Counsellors or Chaplains.
	                        </p>
	                    ]]></Content>
	                    <Content displayName="What does a General Practitioner do?" fixedButtons="true" title="What does a General Practitioner do?" audio="018 What does a General Practitioner Do 2.mp3"><![CDATA[
	                        <p>
	                        A General Practitioner is also called a GP.  A GP is a medical doctor with a degree to diagnose and treat common medical and psychological problems. A GP may prescribe medicine to help with psychological problems.  GPs are a good first contact to help you find the services you need.   They can refer you to an expert like a psychologist, psychiatrist or mental health social worker, who can help you better address your problems. You can find a GP in the Defence and Department of Veterans' Affairs health care systems, through recommendations from people you know, or via a referral from another health provider. If you need medical attention, a prescription, or a referral to a specialist, then your GP is the best place to start.
	                        </p>
	                        ]]></Content>
	                    <Content displayName="What does a Mental Health Social Worker do?" fixedButtons="true" title="What does a Mental Health Social Worker do?" audio="019 What does a MH Social Worker do 2.mp3"><![CDATA[
	                        <p>
	                       Mental health social workers assist people who are struggling with mental health conditions, family and relationship difficulties. Mental health social workers are not medical doctors and cannot prescribe medications. In Australia, mental health social workers are recognised for their ability to provide mental health services under Medicare. You can find a mental health social worker through advice from people you know or referrals from a GP or another mental health provider.  Eligible serving members and ex-serving members may also be able to find a mental health social worker via the VVCS - Veterans and Veterans Families Counselling Service.
	                        </p>
	                        ]]></Content>
	                    <Content displayName="What does a Psychologist do?" fixedButtons="true" title="What does a Psychologist do?" audio="020 What does a Psychologist do 2.mp3"><![CDATA[
	                        <p>
	                        Psychologists work with clients who have serious mental health conditions, including depression, anxiety, PTSD, and substance use problems.  Psychologists work with singles, couples, families and groups. They have the ability to assess, diagnose and treat complex problems relating to mental health. Psychologists are not medical doctors and cannot prescribe medicine. Their role is to provide assessment and counselling. There are psychologists in the community and working throughout Defence and Department of Veterans' Affairs health care systems. You can find a psychologist through advice from people you know, referrals from a GP, or from another mental health provider. The Australian Psychological Society also provides a find a psychologist service which is linked to under the Find Support Tab below. Eligible serving members and ex-serving members may also be able to find a psychologist via the VVCS -Veterans and Veterans Families Counselling Service.
	                        </p>
	                        ]]></Content>
	                    <Content displayName="What does a Psychiatrist do?" fixedButtons="true" title="What does a Psychiatrist do?" audio="021 What does a psychiatrist do 2.mp3"><![CDATA[
	                        <p>
	                        Psychiatrists are medical doctors who treat a variety of mental health problems, including depression, anxiety, PTSD, substance use problems, and severe mental illnesses.  Psychiatrists primarily treat patients with medications that can ease depression and anxiety, help with sleep, and help with symptoms of mental illness.  Some psychiatrists also practice counselling. Psychiatrists work in the community and within the Defence and Department of Veterans' Affairs health care systems. You can find a psychiatrist through advice from people you know, or via a mental health provider, but it is important to get a referral from your GP. 
	                        </p>
	                        ]]></Content>
	                    <Content displayName="What does a Padre or Chaplain do?" fixedButtons="true" title="What does a Pastoral Counsellor or Chaplain do?" audio="022 What does a Padre or Chaplain do 2.mp3"><![CDATA[
	                        <p>
	                        A padre or chaplain is a member of the clergy who provides spiritual support and guidance, conducts religious services in the field, and offers support in emergency situations. Chaplains help people regardless of their faith and religious beliefs. Chaplains are not trained to provide mental health counselling, but they can help you access a specialist like a psychologist, psychiatrist or mental health social worker, who can help you address your emotional difficulties more thoroughly.  If you are looking for spiritual guidance as part of your road to receiving professional care, then perhaps a padre or chaplain is a good place to start.
	                        </p>
	                        ]]></Content>
	                    <Content displayName="Where can I find professional care near me?" fixedButtons="true" title="Where can I find professional care near me?" audio="023 Where can I find professional care near me 2.mp3"><![CDATA[
	                        <p>
	                        Go to the Find Support tab to find web links to resources for counselling and support. Some of the resources are organisations and networks, like the Department of Veterans' Affairs and VVCS - Veterans and Veterans Families Counselling Service, and there are community care options as well. 
	                        </p>
	                        ]]></Content>
	                </Content>
	            </Content>
	        </Content>
	        <Content ui="NavController" displayName="Assess" icon="16-line-chart.png">
	            <Content name="assess" buttonTheme="theme_big_button" displayName="Assess" ui="ButtonGridController" 
	                buttongrid_cellsPerRow="1" buttongrid_buttonjust="left"
	                backButton="Assess" >
                    <Content name="@back" icon="home_icon.png" ref="home"/>
	                <Content name="takeAssessment" displayName="Take Assessment" icon="assess_take.png" ui="QuestionnaireContentController">
	                    <Content name="pcl" file="pcl.xml">
	                        <Content name="pclHelp" displayName="Assessment Help"><![CDATA[
	                            <p>
	                            	This self-assessment tool is called the PTSD Checklist or PCL. This scale has been used with people with PTSD for screening, diagnosis, and monitoring for many years and has been scientifically validated. It includes 17 questions, each of which has 5 possible answers. This assessment cannot tell you if you have PTSD -- only a trained mental health provider can do that. However, it can give you some valuable information about how severe your symptoms are, and if you are getting better or worse over time.  If you are worried that you might have PTSD but you have never been diagnosed, it's important to talk with your GP to get a referral to a mental health provider.
	                            </p>
	                        ]]></Content>
	                        <Content name="pclTooSoon" displayName="Too Early"><![CDATA[
	                            <p>
	                                It has been less than a week since you last did the self-assessment.  The questions are designed to assess your symptoms since the last time you answered, so it is not helpful to do it more than once a week.
	                            </p>
	                        ]]></Content>
	                        <Content name="pclScheduled" displayName="Assessment Scheduled"><![CDATA[
	                            <p>
	                                A notification has been set to remind you to take the PTSD Coach assessment every ${pclScheduledWhen}.
	                            </p>
	                        ]]></Content>
	                        <Content name="pclSchedulePrompt" displayName="Schedule Assessment"><![CDATA[
	                            <p>
	                                You can track your symptoms by scheduling times to take the self-assessment in the future. It is normal for your symptoms to change a bit from day to day.  It is most important to look for a trend over time.  So, you should not do this self-assessment more than once per week. In most cases we suggest one time per month. This will help you see if your symptoms are getting better, worse, or staying the same.  
	                            </p>
	                            <p>
	                                Would you like to set up a follow-up assessment now?
	                            </p>
	                        ]]></Content>
	                        <Content name="pclFeedbackHelp" title="PCL Feedback Help"><![CDATA[
	                        	<p>
	                        		Although this is a scientifically validated questionnaire, the PCL is not intended for self-diagnosis or to replace a trained mental health provider.  
								</p>
								<p>
									However, it can give you some valuable information about how severe your symptoms are, and if you are getting better or worse over time.  If you are concerned that you might have PTSD but you have never been diagnosed, make an appointment with your GP to get a referral to a mental health provider.
								</p>
	                        ]]></Content>
	                        <Content name="pclFeedback" child_help="pclFeedbackHelp">
		                        <Content name="pclHighFirst" displayName="PCL Feedback" title="PCL Feedback" ui="PCLResult"><![CDATA[
		                            <p>
		                                Your score puts you in the high range, which means that you have a lot of PTSD symptoms. If you have already spoken with a health provider and have a diagnosis of PTSD, then this might not be new information. If you have never spoken with a health provider before, now is probably the time to start. 
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                Many people who experience a trauma have this kind of reaction, at least for the first few weeks or months after the trauma. But once the problems have gone on for a while or they start to make it hard to function at home, study, or work, it's time to ask for some help.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                Seeking help will be especially important if you think that you may have other trauma-related problems that this assessment would not identify, such as depression, substance abuse, or anxiety.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                               There are scientifically proven treatments that really work for PTSD. Don't suffer for any longer than you have to. For information on where to find a mental health provider, check out the Find Support section of this app. You can also learn more about professional care in the Learn About PTSD section.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                While there is no replacement for professional face-to-face care, this app can help you learn tools for managing your stress as it comes up. If you are in treatment, this app can be a helpful add-on to face to face care.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                If you ever feel like hurting yourself or someone else, touch the Find Support button below to get help right away. Otherwise, you can take this assessment once per month to see how your symptoms are changing - and hopefully getting better - over time.
		                            </p>
		                        
		                        ]]></Content>
		                        <Content name="pclHighSame" displayName="PCL Feedback" title="PCL Feedback" ui="PCLResult"><![CDATA[
		                            <p>
		                                Your score has not changed since the last time you took the assessment. Symptoms like these may not change much without fully engaging in active treatment with a mental health provider. Even if you are in treatment, it can take a while for problems to decrease.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                Your score still puts you in the high range, which means that you are experiencing a lot of PTSD symptoms. If you have already spoken with a mental health provider and have a diagnosis of PTSD, then this might not be new information. If you have never spoken with a mental health provider before, now is probably the time to start. 
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                Many people who experience a trauma have reactions like yours. Many people who experience a trauma have this kind of reaction, at least for the first few weeks or months after the trauma. But once the problems have gone on for a while or they start to make it hard to function at home, study, or work, it's time to ask for some help.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                Seeking help will be especially important if you think that you may have other trauma-related problems that this assessment would not identify, such as depression, substance abuse, or anxiety.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                               There are scientifically proven treatments that really work for PTSD. Don't suffer for any longer than you have to. For information on where to find a mental health provider, check out the Find Support section of this app. You can also learn more about professional care in the Learn About PTSD section.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                While there is no replacement for professional face-to-face care, this app can help you learn tools for managing your stress as it comes up. If you are in treatment, this app can be a helpful add-on to face to face care.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                If you ever feel like hurting yourself or someone else, touch the Find Support button below to get help right away. Otherwise, you can take this assessment once per month to see how your symptoms are changing - and hopefully getting better - over time.
		                            </p>
		                        ]]></Content>
		                        <Content name="pclHighLower" displayName="PCL Feedback" title="PCL Feedback" ui="PCLResult"><![CDATA[
		                            <p>
		                                Good news: Your score has improved since the last time you took the self-assessment. This means that you are having fewer problems than you were before.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                Still, your score puts you in the high range, which means that you are experiencing a lot of PTSD symptoms. If you have already spoken with a mental health provider and have a diagnosis of PTSD, then this might not be new information. If you have never spoken with a provider before, now is probably the time to start. 
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                               Many people who experience a trauma have reactions like yours. Many people who experience a trauma have this kind of reaction, at least for the first few weeks or months after the trauma. But once the problems have gone on for a while or they start to make it hard to function at home, study, or work, it's time to ask for some help.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                Seeking help will be especially important if you think that you may have other trauma-related problems that this assessment would not identify, such as depression, substance abuse, or anxiety.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                There are scientifically validated treatments that really work for PTSD. Don't suffer for any longer than you have to. For information on where to find a mental health provider, check out the Find Support section of this app. You can also learn more about professional care in the Learn About PTSD section.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                While there is no replacement for professional face-to-face care, this app can help you learn tools for managing your stress as it comes up. If you are in treatment, this app can be a helpful add-on to face to face care.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                If you ever feel like hurting yourself or someone else, touch the Find Support button below to get help right away. Otherwise, you can take this assessment once per month to see how your symptoms are changing - and hopefully getting better - over time.
		                            </p>
		                        ]]></Content>
		                        <Content name="pclHighHigher" displayName="PCL Feedback" title="PCL Feedback" ui="PCLResult"><![CDATA[
		                            <p>
		                                Your score went up since the last time you took the assessment, which means that some things are bothering you more than they were before.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                Your score puts you in the high range, which means that you have a lot of PTSD symptoms. If you have already spoken with a health provider and have a diagnosis of PTSD, then this might not be new information. If you have never spoken with a provider before, now is probably the time to start.  
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                Many people who experience a trauma have this kind of reaction, at least for the first few weeks or months after the trauma. But once the problems have gone on for a while or they start to make it hard to function at home, school, or work, it's time to ask for some help.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                Seeking help will be especially important if you think that you may have other trauma-related problems that this assessment would not identify, such as depression, substance abuse, or anxiety.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                There are scientifically proven treatments that really work for PTSD. Don't suffer for any longer than you have to. For information on where to find a mental health provider, check out the Find Support section of this app. You can also learn more about professional care in the Learn About PTSD section.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                               While there is no replacement for professional face-to-face care, this app can help you learn tools for managing your stress as it comes up. If you are in treatment, this app can be a helpful add-on to face to face care.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                               If you ever feel like hurting yourself or someone else, touch the Find Support button below to get help right away. Otherwise, you can take this assessment once per month to see how your symptoms are changing - and hopefully getting better - over time.
		                            </p>
		                        ]]></Content>
		                        <Content name="pclMidFirst" displayName="PCL Feedback" title="PCL Feedback" ui="PCLResult"><![CDATA[
		                            <p>
		                                Many people who experience a trauma have reactions like yours, at least for the first few weeks or months after the trauma.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                People who have symptoms like yours can often benefit from talking to a mental health provider. For information on where to find one, check out the Find Support section of this app. Seeking help will be especially important if you think that you may have other trauma-related problems that this assessment would not identify, such as depression, substance abuse, or anxiety.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                While there is no replacement for professional face-to-face care, this app can help you learn tools for managing your stress as it comes up. If you are in treatment, this app can be a helpful add-on to face to face care.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                               If you ever feel like hurting yourself or someone else, touch the Find Support button below to get help right away. Otherwise, you can take this assessment once per month to see how your symptoms are changing - and hopefully getting better - over time.
		                            </p>
		                        ]]></Content>
		                        <Content name="pclMidSame" displayName="PCL Feedback" title="PCL Feedback" ui="PCLResult"><![CDATA[
		                            <p>
		                                Your score has not changed since the last time you took the assessment. Symptoms like these may not change much without fully engaging in active treatment with a mental health provider. Even if you are in treatment, it can take a while for problems to decrease.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                Many people who experience a trauma have reactions like yours. Many people who experience a trauma have this kind of reaction, at least for the first few weeks or months after the trauma.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                People who have symptoms like yours can often benefit from talking to a mental health provider. For information on where to find one, check out the Find Support section of this app. Seeking help will be especially important if you think that you may have other trauma-related problems that this assessment would not identify, such as depression, substance abuse, or anxiety.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                               While there is no replacement for professional face-to-face care, this app can help you learn tools for managing your stress as it comes up. If you are in treatment, this app can be a helpful add-on to face to face care.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                               If you ever feel like hurting yourself or someone else, touch the Find Support button below to get help right away. Otherwise, you can take this assessment once per month to see how your symptoms are changing - and hopefully getting better - over time.
		                            </p>
		                        ]]></Content>
		                        <Content name="pclMidLower" displayName="PCL Feedback" title="PCL Feedback" ui="PCLResult"><![CDATA[
		                            <p>
		                                Good news: Your score has improved since the last time you took the self-assessment. This means that you are having fewer problems than you were before.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                Many people who experience a trauma have reactions like yours. Many people who experience a trauma have this kind of reaction, at least for the first few weeks or months after the trauma.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                People who have symptoms like yours can often benefit from talking to a mental health provider. For information on where to find one, check out the Find Support section of this app. Seeking help will be especially important if you think that you may have other trauma-related problems that this assessment would not identify, such as depression, substance abuse, or anxiety.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                While there is no replacement for professional face-to-face care, this app can help you learn tools for managing your stress as it comes up. If you are in treatment, this app can be a helpful add-on to face to face care.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                               If you ever feel like hurting yourself or someone else, touch the Find Support button below to get help right away. Otherwise, you can take this assessment once per month to see how your symptoms are changing - and hopefully getting better - over time.
		                            </p>
		                        ]]></Content>
		                        <Content name="pclMidHigher" displayName="PCL Feedback" title="PCL Feedback" ui="PCLResult"><![CDATA[
		                            <p>
		                            Your score went up since the last time you took the assessment, which means that some things are bothering you more than they were before.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                Many people who experience a trauma have reactions like yours at least for the first few weeks or months after the trauma.

		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                People who have symptoms like yours can often benefit from talking to a mental health provider. For information on where to find one, check out the Find Support section of this app. Seeking help will be especially important if you think that you may have other trauma-related problems that this assessment would not identify, such as depression, substance abuse, or anxiety.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                               While there is no replacement for professional face-to-face care, this app can help you learn tools for managing your stress as it comes up. If you are in treatment, this app can be a helpful add-on to face to face care.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                If you ever feel like hurting yourself or someone else, touch the Find Support button below to get help right away. Otherwise, you can take this assessment once per month to see how your symptoms are changing - and hopefully getting better - over time.
		                            </p>
		                        ]]></Content>
		                        <Content name="pclLowFirst" displayName="PCL Feedback" title="PCL Feedback" ui="PCLResult"><![CDATA[
		                            <p>
		                               You are having some difficulties related to your traumatic experience, but these problems most likely would not be given a diagnosis of Posttraumatic Stress Disorder. 
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                               However, you may still be struggling. Even mild posttraumatic stress can be distressing enough to interrupt your life. Plus, problems like depression, substance abuse, and anxiety can also happen after a trauma and may not register on a PTSD scale. 
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                While there is no replacement for professional face-to-face care, this app can help you learn tools for managing your stress as it comes up. If you are in treatment, this app can be a helpful add-on to face to face care.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                               If you ever feel like hurting yourself or someone else, touch the Find Support button below to get help right away. Otherwise, you can take this assessment once per month to see how your symptoms are changing - and hopefully getting better - over time.
		                            </p>
		                        ]]></Content>
		                        <Content name="pclLowSame" displayName="PCL Feedback" title="PCL Feedback" ui="PCLResult"><![CDATA[
		                            <p>
		                                Your score has not changed since the last time you took the assessment. Symptoms like these may not change much without fully engaging in active treatment with a mental health provider. Even if you are in treatment, it can take a while for problems to decrease.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                You are having some difficulties related to your traumatic experience, but these problems most likely would not be given a diagnosis of Posttraumatic Stress Disorder. 
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                However, you may still be struggling. Even mild posttraumatic stress can be distressing enough to interrupt your life. Plus, problems like depression, substance abuse, and anxiety can also happen after a trauma and may not register on a PTSD scale. 
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                While there is no replacement for professional face-to-face care, this app can help you learn tools for managing your stress as it comes up. If you are in treatment, this app can be a helpful add-on to face to face care.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                If you ever feel like hurting yourself or someone else, touch the Find Support button below to get help right away. Otherwise, you can take this assessment once per month to see how your symptoms are changing - and hopefully getting better - over time.
		                            </p>
		                        ]]></Content>
		                        <Content name="pclLowLower" displayName="PCL Feedback" title="PCL Feedback" ui="PCLResult"><![CDATA[
		                            <p>
		                            Good news: Your score has improved since the last time you took the self-assessment. This means that you are having fewer problems than you were before.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                You are having some difficulties related to your traumatic experience, but these problems most likely would not be given a diagnosis of Posttraumatic Stress Disorder.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                However, you may still be struggling. Even mild posttraumatic stress can be distressing enough to interrupt your life. Plus, problems like depression, substance abuse, and anxiety can also happen after a trauma and may not register on a PTSD scale. 
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                While there is no replacement for professional face-to-face care, this app can help you learn tools for managing your stress as it comes up. If you are in treatment, this app can be a helpful add-on to face to face care.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                If you ever feel like hurting yourself or someone else, touch the Find Support button below to get help right away. Otherwise, you can take this assessment once per month to see how your symptoms are changing - and hopefully getting better - over time.
		                            </p>
		                        ]]></Content>
		                        <Content name="pclLowHigher" displayName="PCL Feedback" title="PCL Feedback" ui="PCLResult"><![CDATA[
		                            <p>
		                            Your score went up since the last time you took the assessment, which means that some things are bothering you more than they were before.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                You are having some difficulties related to your traumatic experience, but these problems would most likely still not be given a diagnosis of Posttraumatic Stress Disorder.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                However, you may still be struggling. Even mild posttraumatic stress can be distressing enough to interrupt your life. Plus, problems like depression, substance abuse, and anxiety can also happen after a trauma and may not register on a PTSD scale. 
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                While there is no replacement for professional face-to-face care, this app can help you learn tools for managing your stress as it comes up. If you are in treatment, this app can be a helpful add-on to face to face care.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                If you ever feel like hurting yourself or someone else, touch the Find Support button below to get help right away. Otherwise, you can take this assessment once per month to see how your symptoms are changing - and hopefully getting better - over time.
		                            </p>
		                        ]]></Content>
		                        <Content name="pclBottomFirst" displayName="PCL Feedback" title="PCL Feedback" ui="PCLResult"><![CDATA[
		                            <p>
		                                You do not have any symptoms of Posttraumatic Stress Disorder at this time. 
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                However, this assessment will not pick up other problems that can be related to trauma such as depression, substance abuse, and anxiety.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                If you are stressed, go see a mental health provider, regardless of the outcome of this assessment. A mental health provider will be able to help you understand what is going on and how you can fix it.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                Even if you do not have PTSD, this app can help you learn tools for managing your stress as it comes up. If you are in treatment, this app can be a helpful add-on to face to face care.
		                            </p>
		                        ]]></Content>
		                        <Content name="pclBottomSame" displayName="PCL Feedback" title="PCL Feedback" ui="PCLResult"><![CDATA[
		                            <p>
		                            Your score has not changed since the last time you took this assessment. You still do not have any symptoms of Posttraumatic Stress Disorder. 
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                However, this assessment will not pick up other problems that can be related to trauma such as depression, substance abuse, and anxiety.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                If you are stressed, go see a mental health provider, regardless of the outcome of this assessment. A mental health provider will be able to help you understand what is going on and how you can fix it.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                Even if you do not have PTSD, this app can help you learn tools for managing your stress as it comes up. If you are in treatment, this app can be a helpful add-on to face to face care.
		                            </p>
		                        ]]></Content>
		                        <Content name="pclBottomLower" displayName="PCL Feedback" title="PCL Feedback" ui="PCLResult"><![CDATA[
		                            <p>
		                                Good news: Your score has improved since the last time you took the self-assessment. This means that you are having fewer problems than you were before.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                You do not have any symptoms of Posttraumatic Stress Disorder at this time. 
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                However, this assessment will not pick up other problems that can be related to trauma such as depression, substance abuse, and anxiety.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                If you are stressed, go see a mental health provider, regardless of the outcome of this assessment. A mental health provider will be able to help you understand what is going on and how you can fix it.
		                            </p>
		                            <p>
		                                Even if you do not have PTSD, this app can help you learn tools for managing your stress as it comes up. If you are in treatment, this app can be a helpful add-on to face to face care.
		                            </p>
		                        ]]></Content>
		                    </Content>
	                    </Content>
					</Content>
	                <Content name="trackHistory" displayName="Symptom History" title="Symptom History" icon="assess_track.png">
	                    <Content name="@inline" predicate="!dae.pclHistoryExists">
	                        Once you take the self-assessment your results will show up here as a graph. You can watch your scores change over time. This is an opportunity to get feedback on how severe your symptoms are, and if they are getting better or worse over time.  Remember, no one will see your results other than you, although you can choose to share the results with your mental health provider, who may then opt to make use of these results in your care. Take the self-assessment now for more information.
	                        <Content name="@button" displayName="Take Assessment Now" ref="takeAssessment"/>
	                    </Content>
	                    <Content name="@inline" predicate="dae.pclHistoryExists" ui="PCLHistoryViewController">
	                    	<Content name="@button" displayName="E-mail Physician" enabledPredicate="dae.pclHistoryExists">
		                    	<Content name="@inline" predicate="!dae.preferredContactSet" title="No Preferred Contact">
									You haven't designated a contact as your preferred mental health professional.  Do this before sending your PCL scores.
									<Content name="@button" displayName="Go to Setup" ref="setup" refAction="pop"/>
		                    	</Content>
		                    	<Content name="@inline" predicate="dae.preferredContactSet" title="E-mail PCL Results">
		                    		You have chosen to email the results of your PCL assessments to your mental health provider. This could be your GP, psychiatrist, psychologist, mental health social worker, or counsellor. Please note that your mental health provider may or may not choose to use these self-assessment results as part of your care. Opting to send the results should not be viewed as a method of alerting your mental health provider to an emergency situation.
									<Content name="@button" displayName="Send the E-mail" action="sendEmail"/>
		                    	</Content>
	                    	</Content>
	                    </Content>
	                    <Content name="@help" title="History Help">
	                    	This graph shows how your scores on the self-assessment have changed over time. It is normal for your symptoms to go up and down a bit from time to time.  It is most important to look for a trend over time.  Lower scores mean that you have less severe symptoms. So if your line is going down, that is good news. Higher scores mean that you have more severe symptoms, so if your line is going up, you may want to check in with your mental health professional and let him or her know (or get a mental health professional if you don't already have one). Scores can sometimes also go up as you start working on your PTSD and facing uncomfortable thoughts and memories, but your mental health professional will be able to help monitor this.
	                    </Content>
	                </Content>
	            </Content>
	        </Content>
	        <Content ui="NavController" displayName="Manage" icon="28-star.png">
	            <Content name="manage" buttonTheme="theme_big_button" ui="SegmentedToggleController" title="Manage" backButton="Manage">
                    <Content name="@back" icon="home_icon.png" ref="home"/>
	                <Content name="@help" icon="help_icon.png" title="Manage Help" ui="ContentViewController"><![CDATA[
	                    <p>
	                    	This part of the app contains tools and techniques to help manage your feelings and reactions. It can help you bring your PTSD symptoms under control. You can use this part of the app in 2 ways. The Symptoms tab allows you to tell the app which type of symptom you are experiencing, and the app will randomly generate a tool that works well with that symptom.  Alternatively, you can use the Tools tab and select a tool directly. 
	                    </p>
	                    <p>
	                        People who have experienced traumatic events have different experiences as they recover, but the problems below are common following a trauma. You may experience some, all, or none of the following problems.
                        </p>
                        <ul>
                            <li><b>Reminders of trauma:</b> Frequently having upsetting thoughts or memories about the trauma, feeling as if it's happening again, and/or feeling very distressed when reminded of it.</li> 
                            <li><b>Avoiding triggers:</b> Making an effort to avoid thoughts, feelings, conversations, places or people because they remind you of the trauma.</li>
                            <li><b>Disconnected from people:</b> Feeling distant from others, trouble feeling love, and/or feeling alienated and alone.</li>
                            <li><b>Disconnected from reality:</b> Feeling disconnected from the world, other people, one's body, or oneself—detached, "foggy," "in a dream," "out of body," or as if things feel unreal.  </li>
                            <li><b>Sad / Hopeless:</b> Feeling sad, down, blue or depressed, not having interest in activities that used to be enjoyed, or in life in general, feeling a sense of meaninglessness and/or hopelessness.</li>
                            <li><b>Anxious / Worried:</b> Being jumpy and easily startled, being tense and "on guard" most of the time.</li>
                            <li><b>Angry:</b> Being easily irritated, having angry outbursts, feeling on edge or mistrustful.</li>
                            <li><b>Trouble Sleeping:</b> Trouble falling and/or staying asleep, having nightmares, waking in a cold sweat or in a panic.</li>
                        </ul>
	                ]]></Content>
	                <Content name="toolPicker" displayName="Tools" backButton="Tools" ui="ToolListController" selectionVariable="preselectedExercise" selectionBumpsScore="true">
	                </Content>
	                <Content name="symptomPicker" displayName="Symptoms" backButton="Symptoms" ui="ContentListViewController" selectionVariable="symptom">
	                    <Symptom name="reexperiencing" displayName="Reminded of Trauma"/>
	                    <Symptom name="avoidance" displayName="Avoiding Triggers"/>
	                    <Symptom name="isolation" displayName="Disconnected from People"/>
	                    <Symptom name="dissociation" displayName="Disconnected from Reality"/>
	                    <Symptom name="hopeless" displayName="Sad / Hopeless"/>
	                    <Symptom name="anxiety" displayName="Worried / Anxious"/>
	                    <Symptom name="anger" displayName="Angry"/>
	                    <Symptom name="sleep" displayName="Unable to Sleep"/>
	                </Content>
	            </Content>
				<Content name="sudsprompt" ui="SUDSController" title="Distress Meter" fixedButtons="true" buttonTheme="theme_big_button" backButton="Distress" help="sudshelp"><![CDATA[
					<p>
						SUDS are "Subjective Units of Distress" and are a handy way of quickly assessing your level of distress in a situation.  You can rate your distress level on a scale of 0 to 10. Distress includes everything negative you are feeling, including anger, sadness, fear, and so on, all in one score. Zero means no distress at all and ten means the worst distress you could imagine. 
					</p>
					<p>
						This will help you monitor your distress levels and figure out which tools in this app work best for you.
					</p>
					]]>
					<Content name="sudshelp" displayName="More About Distress"><![CDATA[
							<p>
								You can rate your distress level - including negative feelings such as stress, anger, physical tension, and more, all rolled into one - on a scale of 0 to 10. This will help you monitor your distress levels and figure out which tools work best for you. You can also use it in your daily life to check in and see how you're doing.
							</p>
							<p>
								It may seem strange at first, but sometimes we can get caught up in an all-or-nothing way of thinking- either "I'm totally uncomfortable" or "I'm totally fine". The distress score can help you learn to see the shades of grey, and help you see that even when things aren't perfect, they may be improving. It can also help you learn to recognise what triggers distress for you.
							</p>
					]]></Content>
				</Content>
				<Content name="exercise" ui="ToolController">
						<ExerciseCategory name="relaxation" child_weight="5.0" displayName="Relaxation Exercises" child_variable_tooltype="the relaxation tool" child_helpsWithSymptoms="reexperiencing avoidance dissociation anxiety anger sleep" child_ui="SimpleExerciseController">
							<Content weight="30.0" name="deepBreathing" title="Deep Breathing" displayName="Deep Breathing" ui="SimpleExerciseIntroController">
								Slowing down and deepening your breathing can help you calm down when you feel distress. Put on your headphones or go somewhere private and quiet to be led through the exercise.
								<Content name="@help" displayName="Deep Breathing">
									This activity will guide you through a brief exercise in which you take slower, deeper breaths to help you relax. Taking slow, deep breaths helps you balance the carbon dioxide and oxygen in your blood. This calms your nervous system, creating a "relaxation response." Deep breathing exercises can help manage stress and insomnia, focus the mind, and improve health.
								</Content>
								<Content
                                    name="@next"
                                    displayName="Begin"
                                    title="Deep Breathing"
                                    audio="024 Relax Breathing MST.mp3"
                                    ui="BreathingController"
                                    initialFadeInTime="38"
                                    initialBreathTime="46"
                                    secondBreathTime="76.5"
                                    firstCountingBreathTime="90"
                                    
                                    >
									Listen to the audio and follow along with the exercise.
									
				                    <Content name="breathe_background" image="glass_sphere_outline.png" />
				                    <Content name="breathe_in" image="glass_sphere_green.png" />
				                    <Content name="breathe_hold" image="glass_sphere_yellow.png" />
				                    <Content name="breathe_out" image="glass_sphere_red.png" />
				                    
									<Caption start="0:00" end="0:07"><![CDATA[To prepare, sit down and make yourself comfortable so that you can practice along as you listen to and watch the demonstration. ]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="0:8" end="0:16"><![CDATA[Later, when you practice, you can do this exercise sitting, standing up, or lying down - whatever works for you.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="0:18" end="0:32"><![CDATA[Although this exercise should be safe for almost anyone, if you have difficulty breathing, or feel out of breath, or begin to feel dizzy, nervous, or out of control, you can adjust your breathing pace, or go back to breathing normally.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="0:33" end="0:39"><![CDATA[The goal is just to slow down a bit to allow your system to relax.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="0:40" end="0:45"><![CDATA[Place one hand on your stomach, and one on your chest.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="0:46" end="0:56"><![CDATA[Breathe in by taking air deep into your stomach - allow your stomach to expand out while your shoulders and chest stay relaxed.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="0:57" end="1:04"><![CDATA[Now breathe out, slowly, allowing the air you exhale to deflate your stomach.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="1:05" end="1:07"><![CDATA[Pause naturally.]]></Caption>
                                <Caption start="1:08" end="1:15"><![CDATA[You may find it easier to breathe through your nose, but do what's comfortable for you.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="1:16" end="1:20"><![CDATA[Breathe in, taking air deep into your stomach.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="1:21" end="1:28"><![CDATA[Now breathe out, slowly, but naturally.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="1:30" end="1:33"><![CDATA[Breathe in, taking air deep into your stomach.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="1:34" end="1:36"><![CDATA[Say the number "1" to yourself.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="1:37" end="1:42"><![CDATA[Breathe out, slowly, saying the word "Relax" to yourself.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="1:44" end="1:50"><![CDATA[Breathe in, taking air deep into your stomach, and think the number "2".]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="1:51" end="1:57"><![CDATA[Now exhale all of the air, and think the word "Relax".]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="1:58" end="2:04"><![CDATA[Breathe in - think the number "3".]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="2:05" end="2:11"><![CDATA[Now exhale - think the word "Relax"]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="2:12" end="2:18"><![CDATA[Breathe in - think the number "4".]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="2:19" end="2:25"><![CDATA[Now breathe out, slowly - think the word "Relax".]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="2:26" end="2:32"><![CDATA[Breathe in - five.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="2:33" end="2:39"><![CDATA[Breathe out - relax.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="2:40" end="2:46"><![CDATA[Breathe in - six.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="2:47" end="2:53"><![CDATA[Breathe out - relax.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="2:54" end="3:00"><![CDATA[Breathe in - seven.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="3:01" end="3:07"><![CDATA[Breathe out- relax.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="3:08" end="3:14"><![CDATA[Breathe in - eight.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="3:15" end="3:21"><![CDATA[Breathe out - relax.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="3:22" end="3:28"><![CDATA[Counting backwards now, breathe in - eight.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="3:29" end="3:35"><![CDATA[Breathe out - relax.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="3:36" end="3:42"><![CDATA[Breathe in - seven.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="3:43" end="3:49"><![CDATA[Breathe out - relax.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="3:50" end="3:56"><![CDATA[Breathe in - six.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="3:57" end="4:03"><![CDATA[Breathe out slowly - relax.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="4:04" end="4:10"><![CDATA[Breathe in - five.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="4:11" end="4:17"><![CDATA[Breathe out - relax.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="4:18" end="4:24"><![CDATA[Breathe in - four.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="4:25" end="4:31"><![CDATA[Breathe out - relax.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="4:32" end="4:38"><![CDATA[Breathe in - three.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="4:39" end="4:45"><![CDATA[Breathe out - relax.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="4:46" end="4:52"><![CDATA[Breathe in - two.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="4:53" end="4:59"><![CDATA[Breathe out - relax.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="5:00" end="5:06"><![CDATA[Breathe in - one.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="5:07" end="5:11"><![CDATA[Breathe out - relax.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="5:12" end="5:14"><![CDATA[Well done.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="5:15" end="5:28"><![CDATA[Even as you end this exercise, you can continue to allow your breathing to be deeper and slower - take your time as you open your eyes, and bring your attention back to your surroundings.]]></Caption>
							</Content>
						</Content>
						<Content weight="50.0" name="progressiveRelaxation" displayName="Progressive Relaxation" title="Progressive Relaxation" ui="SimpleExerciseIntroController">
							You are about to be led through a relaxation exercise focused on visualising something pleasant. This exercise takes about 4 minutes. It has accompanying audio, so you will have to find a quiet place or put on your headphones now. Do not do this exercise while driving.
							<Content name="@help" displayName="Progressive Relaxation"><![CDATA[
								<p>
									This exercise will guide you, either sitting comfortably or lying down, through tensing and relaxing a sequence of muscle groups. This allows muscles to relax more deeply than usual. This exercise can help decrease heart rate and blood pressure, slow breathing, decrease muscle tension, and clear thinking.  
								</p>
								<p>
									This exercise is also great because over time you can train yourself to really know what tense muscles feel like and what relaxed muscles feel like.   Then, when you recognise that your muscles are tense or becoming tense you can immediately switch your muscles to the more relaxed state because you have trained yourself to know how relaxed muscles feel.  
								</p>
							]]></Content>
							<Content name="@next" displayName="Begin" title="Progressive Relaxation" audio="025 Relax Progressive Muscle Relaxation MST.mp3" ui="PMRController">
			                    <Content name="resources" image="body.png">
			                        <Content image="body_arms.png" start="92" end="160" center="-60,20" scale="3" />
			                        <Content image="body_head.png" start="180" end="262" center="0,135" scale="5" />
			                        <Content image="body_shoulders.png" start="278" end="310" center="0,100" scale="3" />
			                        <Content image="body_stomach.png" start="356" end="399" center="0,20" scale="5" />
			                        <Content image="body_butt.png" start="426" end="490" center="0,-20" scale="3" />
			                        <Content image="body_feet.png" start="514" end="575" center="0,-130" scale="3" />
			                        <Content image="body_all.png" start="682" alphaDuration="20" />
			                    </Content>
			                    
								<Caption start="0:00" end="0:04"><![CDATA[To prepare, sit down and make yourself comfortable.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="0:05" end="0:13"><![CDATA[Please note that if you have injuries such as back pain or a knee injury, you should avoid tensing muscles that might affect that injury.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="0:14" end="0:20"><![CDATA[To begin, close your eyes, and take a deep breath into your stomach.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="0:21" end="0:24"><![CDATA[Then exhale with a sigh.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="0:25" end="0:38"><![CDATA[Again, take a deep breath, and imagine clean air going down your throat, and filling your lungs, and then exhale with a sigh.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="0:40" end="0:50"><![CDATA[Take another deep breath, and, as you release it, think the word "Relax", silently to yourself.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="0:52" end="1:03"><![CDATA[Allow your breath to be slow and rhythmic, inhaling and exhaling at a pace that is comfortable for you.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="1:06" end="1:20"><![CDATA[As you continue to breathe, continue to say the word "Relax" to yourself, slowly and calmly, each time you breathe out.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="1:22" end="1:30"><![CDATA[As you do this, imagine that the tension throughout your body begins to melt away.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="1:32" end="1:46"><![CDATA[To begin, clench both of your fists, and bend your elbows, drawing your forearms and hands up towards your shoulders, tightening your biceps to do so.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="1:47" end="1:56"><![CDATA[Hold the muscles in your hands and arms tight, and notice the sensations of pulling, discomfort, and tightness.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="1:58" end="2:11"><![CDATA[Hold the tension, while you take a deep breath into your stomach, and then slowly exhale, as you release the muscles of your hands and arms.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="2:13" end="2:22"><![CDATA[Let your hands and fingers relax completely, and let your arms become limp at your side or in your lap.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="2:24" end="2:37"><![CDATA[Feel the sensation of relaxation, as the tension drains away from your arms and hands, and allow the muscles to become looser and looser.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="2:40" end="2:45"><![CDATA[You may notice that they feel heavier and warmer.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="2:46" end="2:57"><![CDATA[Breathing in slowly, and out, thinking the word "Relax" each time you breathe out.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="3:04" end="3:20"><![CDATA[Now bring your attention to your face, and tighten your forehead, the muscles around your eyes and your jaw, by squeezing your eyes tight, clenching your jaw, and wrinkling your forehead and nose.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="3:22" end="3:27"><![CDATA[Feel the wrinkling and pulling sensations across the forehead and the top of your head.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="3:28" end="3:33"><![CDATA[Feel the tightness around your eyes and cheeks, and the tension in your jaw.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="3:34" end="3:46"><![CDATA[Hold that tension, and take a deep breath into your stomach, and then slowly exhale, as you let your face relax completely.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="3:47" end="4:05"><![CDATA[Feel the muscles in your forehead becoming smooth and limp, the muscles of your cheeks and eyes softening, your jaw relaxing, let your lips part slightly, and let your jaw hang loose.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="4:06" end="4:22"><![CDATA[Notice the tension melting away; feel your muscles becoming softer, more relaxed, and feel the warmth and lightness that replaces the tension that was there before.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="4:24" end="4:34"><![CDATA[Contine to breathe slowly and gently, thinking the word "relax" each time you exhale.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="4:38" end="4:45"><![CDATA[Tighten your shoulders by raising them up as if you were going to touch them to your ears, tensing without straining. ]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="4:46" end="5:08"><![CDATA[Feel the tension in your shoulders radiating down into your back and up into your neck and the top of your back. Hold that. Notice those sensations and take a deep breath into your stomach, and then slowly exhale as you relax your shoulders. ]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="5:10" end="5:19"><![CDATA[Let your shoulders droop down and let your neck relax completely, feeling very relaxed]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="5:20" end="5:27"><![CDATA[Notice the contrast between the tightness you felt and the relaxation you feel now. ]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="5:29" end="5:45"><![CDATA[Let your head relax, as if there's nothing holding it, except the support behind it. Feel the sense of relaxation around your neck and shoulders as you let the tension drain away]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="5:47" end="5:52"><![CDATA[Continue to breathe slowly and deeply.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="5:56" end="5:59"><![CDATA[Now bring your attention to your stomach.  ]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="6:00" end="6:06"><![CDATA[Tighten the muscles of your stomach by pulling your stomach in towards your spine tightly. ]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="6:07" end="6:20"><![CDATA[Hold that pose. Feel the sensation of the tension. Hold it while you are taking a deep breath, and then slowly exhale as you relax your muscles. ]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="6:22" end="6:37"><![CDATA[Imagine a wave of relaxtion spreading through your stomach. Allow the muscles of your stomach to be soft and relaxed, letting go more and more.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="6:39" end="7:01"><![CDATA[Notice the difference between the tension you felt, and the relaxation you feel now. Let any remaining tension melt away, continuing to breathe gently in and out, feeling yourself become calmer and more relaxed.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="7:06" end="7:24"><![CDATA[Now tighten your buttocks by squeezing them together and at the same time, squeeze the muscles of your thighs. You can lift your feet up to help tense your leg muscles. Notice the sensations of tightness, pulling and constriction.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="7:25" end="7:39"><![CDATA[Hold on to that tension, and focus on it, and take a deep breath. Then slowly exhale as you relax your buttocks and thighs.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="7:41" end="7:51"><![CDATA[Allow your muscles to relax completely, and to let any tension drain away, melting away.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="7:53" end="8:02"><![CDATA[Feel how the muscles of your hips and legs feel different now than they did when you were clenching them.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="8:03" end="8:30"><![CDATA[Really notice the difference. Continue to let go further and further, experiencing an even deeper relaxation, breathing in and out, slowly and gently, in and out.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="8:34" end="8:42"><![CDATA[Now tighten the muscles of your calves and your feet as you flex your feet, pulling your toes towards you. ]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="8:43" end="8:46"><![CDATA[Flex these muscles carefully to avoid a cramp.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="8:47" end="9:08"><![CDATA[Continue to flex your feet, feeling the muscles of your calves, feet and toes tighten and pull. Hold the tension for another second and take a deep breath. And now, slowly, exhale, release. ]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="9:10" end="9:33"><![CDATA[As your muscles relax, notice how the sensations in your calves and feet change, perhaps feeling softer, or lighter. Really notice how the sensations of tension are different from the sensations of relaxation you are now experiencing. ]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="9:35" end="9:44"><![CDATA[With each breath, allow more tension to drain from your calves, relaxing more and more deeply. ]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="9:46" end="10:14"><![CDATA[Continue to breath slowly, thinking the word "relax" each time you exhale, continuing to let any remaining tension drain away, breathing in and out, in and out.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="10:16" end="10:22"><![CDATA[Relax, relax.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="10:24" end="11:17"><![CDATA[Now that your whole body is feeling relaxed and comfortable, feel that sense of warmth and calmness spread over your whole body, continuing to breath naturally, smoothly and steadily, letting the breath in and out, slowly and regularly, thinking the word "relax", every time you breath out, breathing in and out, in and out. ]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="11:22" end="11:31"><![CDATA[As you continue to breathe, imagine a wave of relaxation slowly spreading throughout your body. ]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="11:32" end="11:44"><![CDATA[Starting at your head and gradually penetrating all of your muscles, all of the cells in your body, all the way down to your toes.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="11:46" end="12:12"><![CDATA[Allow yourself to relax completely, continuing to breathe slowly and smoothly, sinking into that feeling of relaxation and noticing how it feels so that you will be able to access it and recreate it later on your own.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="12:17" end="12:40"><![CDATA[In a moment, I'm going to count from 5 to 1. As I do, you will gradually feel more and more alert. When I get to 3, open your eyes, and when I get to 1, you will feel alert and refreshed and ready for the rest of your day.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="12:43" end="13:12"><![CDATA[5, 4, beginning to shift your body, feeling a bit more awake now, 3, opening your eyes, 2, a bit more awake now, 1.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="13:13" end="13:19"><![CDATA[Now you are feeling refreshed, alert, and relaxed.]]></Caption>
							</Content>
						</Content>
						<Content name="positiveImagery1" displayName="Positive Imagery - Beach" title="Positive Imagery" ui="SimpleExerciseIntroController">
							You are about to be led through a relaxation exercise focused on visualizing something pleasant. This exercise takes about 4 minutes. 
							It has accompanying audio, so you will have to find a quiet place or put on your headphones now.  Do not do this exercise while driving.
							<Content name="@help" displayName="Positive Imagery">
								This exercise will guide you in imagining a pleasant scene in order to reduce stress and help you relax. With this guided imagery, you can 
								relax your muscles and breathe more deeply while you focus on the relaxing scene in order to relax more deeply.
							</Content>
							<Content name="@next" displayName="Begin" title="Positive Imagery" audio="028 Relax Beach MST.mp3" ui="RelaxationController" image="imagery_beach.jpg">
								<![CDATA[Listen to the audio and follow along with the exercise.]]>
								<Caption start="0:00" end="0:08"><![CDATA[First, remove distractions - turn off the telephone, let others know not to bother you.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="0:09" end="0:14"><![CDATA[Make yourself comfortable, so that your thoughts are on the image and nothing else.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="0:15" end="0:19"><![CDATA[Sit, or lie down, in a quiet, comfortable place.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="0:21" end="0:24"><![CDATA[Then, mentally scan your body for tense muscles.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="0:25" end="0:30"><![CDATA[If you find a muscle that tense, or clenched, relax it.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="0:32" end="0:43"><![CDATA[During the imagery exercise, involve all of your senses in the image: sight, sound, smell, touch, and taste.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="0:45" end="0:50"><![CDATA[Get completely focused.  The more focused you are, the better.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="0:52" end="0:56"><![CDATA[Close your eyes, or lower your gaze.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="0:58" end="1:08"><![CDATA[In your mind's eye, you see yourself descending down a long, narrow, wooden stairway, toward a beautiful, inviting beach.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="1:09" end="1:20"><![CDATA[Your bare feet feel the rough, weathered step.  And with each step, you feel more and more tension gently melting away from your body.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="1:21" end="1:34"><![CDATA[As you continue down the stairway, you notice the ocean is a deep shade of blue, with the fine, white crests of the waves sweeping towards the shore.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="1:35" end="1:42"><![CDATA[You reach the end of the stairway, and step down, sinking into the warmth.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="1:43" end="1:53"><![CDATA[As you soak in the warmth of the sun, a soothing sensation of relaxation gently melts through your entire body.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="1:54" end="2:05"><![CDATA[The gentle sounds of the water lapping up onto the beach calm your mind, and allow you to feel even more relaxed.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="2:09" end="2:17"><![CDATA[You begin walking slowly towards the edge of the water, and feel the warm sun on your face and shoulders.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="2:19" end="2:26"><![CDATA[The salty smell of the ocean air invigorates you, and you take in a deep breath.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="2:27" end="2:34"><![CDATA[Breathe slowly out, and feel more relaxed and refreshed.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="2:36" end="2:45"><![CDATA[Finally, you reach the water's edge, and you enjoy the gentle waves as they flow over your toes and ankles.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="2:47" end="3:02"><![CDATA[You watch the waves glide slowly towards you, gently sweeping around your feet, and the trails of ocean water that flow slowly back out again.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="3:04" end="3:16"><![CDATA[The cool water feels soft and comforting, as you enjoy a few moments, allowing yourself to gaze out on the far-reaching horizon.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="3:17" end="3:24"><![CDATA[Overhead, you notice two birds gracefully soaring high above the ocean water.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="3:25" end="3:29"><![CDATA[And you can hear their soft cries becoming faint as they glide away.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="3:30" end="3:40"><![CDATA[All of these sights, sounds, and sensations allow you to relax and let go, more and more.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="3:44" end="3:49"><![CDATA[After a few moments, you begin slowly strolling down the beach, at the water's edge.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="3:50" end="4:01"><![CDATA[You feel a warm, gentle breeze, lightly pressing against your back, and, with every step, you feel yourself relaxing, more and more.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="4:03" end="4:19"><![CDATA[As you walk down the beach, you notice the details of sights and sounds around you, and the soothing sensations of the sun, the gentle breeze, and the sand below your feet.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="4:22" end="4:36"><![CDATA[As you continue your leisurely walk down the beach, you notice a colourful beach chair, resting in a nice, peaceful spot, where the powdery, soft sand lies undisturbed.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="4:37" end="4:47"><![CDATA[You approach this comfortable-looking beach chair, then you sit down, lie back, and settle in.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="4:49" end="5:04"><![CDATA[You take in a long, deep breath, breathe slowly out, and feel even more relaxed and comfortable, resting in your chair.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="5:06" end="5:14"><![CDATA[For a few moments more, let yourself enjoy the sights and sounds of this beautiful day on the beach.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="5:19" end="5:30"><![CDATA[When you're ready, gently bring your attention back to the room, still letting yourself feel relaxed and comfortable, sitting where you are.]]></Caption>
							</Content>
						</Content>
						<Content name="positiveImagery2" displayName="Positive Imagery - Forest" title="Positive Imagery" ui="SimpleExerciseIntroController">
							You are about to be led through a relaxation exercise focused on visualizing something pleasant. This exercise takes about 4 minutes. 
							It has accompanying audio, so you will have to find a quiet place or put on your headphones now. 
							<Content name="@help" displayName="Positive Imagery">
								This exercise will guide you in imagining a pleasant scene in order to reduce stress and help you relax. With this guided imagery, you can 
								relax your muscles and breathe more deeply while you focus on the relaxing scene in order to relax more deeply.
							</Content>
							<Content name="@next" displayName="Begin" title="Positive Imagery" audio="027 Relax Forest Scene MST.mp3" ui="RelaxationController" image="imagery_forest.jpg">
								<![CDATA[Listen to the audio and follow along with the exercise.]]>
								<Caption start="0:00" end="0:07"><![CDATA[First, remove distractions - turn off the telephone, let others know not to bother you.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="0:09" end="0:14"><![CDATA[Make yourself comfortable, so that your thoughts are on the image and nothing else.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="0:15" end="0:19"><![CDATA[Sit, or lie down, in a quiet, comfortable place]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="0:21" end="0:24"><![CDATA[Mentally scan your body for tense muscles.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="0:25" end="0:30"><![CDATA[If you find a muscle that is tense, or clenched, relax it.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="0:32" end="0:43"><![CDATA[During the imagery exercise, involve all of your senses in the image: sight, sound, smell, touch, and taste.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="0:45" end="0:50"><![CDATA[Get completely focused.  The more focused you are, the better.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="0:52" end="0:55"><![CDATA[Close your eyes, or lower your gaze.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="0:59" end="1:03"><![CDATA[Imagine that you are walking down a path, into a lush forest ]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="1:04" end="1:12"><![CDATA[As you walk along the path, you completely take in the sights, smells, and feel of the place.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="1:13" end="1:20"><![CDATA[All around you are trees, grasses, mossy ground cover and fragrant flowers. ]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="1:22" end="1:29"><![CDATA[You hear the soothing sounds of birds chirping, and the wind as it gently blows through the treetops.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="1:31" end="1:39"><![CDATA[You smell the rich dampness of the forest floor. The smells of moist vegetation and new growth.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="1:40" end="1:46"><![CDATA[Through gaps in the treetops, you see the sun high in the cloudless blue sky.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="1:48" end="1:59"><![CDATA[The sun is dispersed through the canopy of the treetops and filters down onto the forest floor, creating intricate patterns of light and shadow.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="2:01" end="2:09"><![CDATA[With each breath you take in this place, you feel a deep sense of peace and relaxation.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="2:12" end="2:19"><![CDATA[You soon come to a clearing.  There are several flat rocks in the clearing surrounded by a soft moss. ]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="2:20" end="2:23"><![CDATA[A small stream runs along the rocks. ]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="2:24" end="2:31"><![CDATA[You lie back on one of the rocks, or on the cushiony moss, and put your feet into the cool water. ]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="2:32" end="2:40"><![CDATA[You feel the warm sun and a gentle light breeze through your hair and across your skin. ]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="2:42" end="2:50"><![CDATA[The sparkling clear water rushes around multicoloured rocks, making little whirlpools and eddies. ]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="2:51" end="2:56"><![CDATA[You put your hand into the water and lift a handful to your lips. ]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="2:57" end="2:59"><![CDATA[The water is cool and refreshing. ]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="3:00" end="3:15"><![CDATA[You close your eyes and listen to the water trickling around the rocks. You bathe in the warm sun, and feel as though you're floating, relaxing deeper and deeper.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="3:18" end="3:32"><![CDATA[You let yourself sink further into relaxation while continuing to be aware of the sights, smells, and feel of the forest around you.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="3:33" end="3:43"><![CDATA[You allow yourself to let go of any concerns or worries, and to feel completely refreshed and rejuvenated in this place.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="3:45" end="3:52"><![CDATA[When you're ready, imagine that you slowly get up and leave the clearing. ]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="3:53" end="4:04"><![CDATA[As you walk back down the path through the forest, fully take in this place, and realise that you may return whenever you wish by the same path.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="4:05" end="4:11"><![CDATA[Each time you enter this place, you will feel relaxed and at peace.]]></Caption>
							</Content>
						</Content>
						<Content name="positiveImagery3" displayName="Positive Imagery - Country" title="Positive Imagery" ui="SimpleExerciseIntroController">
							You are about to be led through a relaxation exercise focused on visualizing something pleasant. This exercise takes about 4 minutes. 
							It has accompanying audio, so you will have to find a quiet place or put on your headphones now. 
							<Content name="@help" displayName="Positive Imagery">
								This exercise will guide you in imagining a pleasant scene in order to reduce stress and help you relax. With this guided imagery, you can relax your muscles and breathe more deeply while you focus on the relaxing scene in order to relax more deeply.
							</Content>
							<Content name="@next" displayName="Begin" title="Positive Imagery" audio="026 Relax Country Road MST.mp3" ui="RelaxationController" image="imagery_country_road.jpg">
								<![CDATA[Listen to the audio and follow along with the exercise.]]>
								<Caption start="0:00" end="0:07"><![CDATA[First, remove distractions - turn off the telephone, let others know not to bother you.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="0:09" end="0:15"><![CDATA[Make yourself comfortable, so that your thoughts are on the image and nothing else.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="0:16" end="0:27"><![CDATA[Sit, or lie down, in a quiet, comfortable place, then, mentally scan your body for tense muscles.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="0:28" end="0:33"><![CDATA[If you find a muscle that's tense, or clenched, relax it.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="0:36" end="0:50"><![CDATA[During the imagery exercise, involve all of your senses in the image: sight, sound, smell, touch, and taste.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="0:52" end="0:58"><![CDATA[Get completely focused.  The more focused you are, the better.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="1:00" end="1:03"><![CDATA[Close your eyes, or lower your gaze.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="1:06" end="1:22"><![CDATA[Imagine yourself walking along an old country road - the sun is warm on your back, the birds are singing, the air is calm and fragrant.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="1:24" end="1:28"><![CDATA[After a few steps, you come across an old gate.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="1:29" end="1:34"><![CDATA[The gate creaks as you open it and go through.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="1:35" end="1:50"><![CDATA[You find yourself in an overgrown garden, flowers growing where they have seeded themselves, vines climbing over a fallen tree, green grass, and shade trees.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="1:53" end="1:57"><![CDATA[Breathe deeply, smelling the flowers.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="1:59" end="2:03"><![CDATA[Listen to the birds and insects.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="2:04" end="2:09"><![CDATA[Feel the gentle breeze, warm against your skin.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="2:11" end="2:19"><![CDATA[You walk leisurely up a gentle slope behind the garden, and come to a wooded area, where the trees become denser.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="2:20" end="2:23"><![CDATA[The sun is filtered through the leaves.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="2:24" end="2:27"><![CDATA[The air feels mild, and a bit cooler.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="2:28" end="2:32"><![CDATA[You become aware of the sound of a nearby creek.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="2:33" end="2:43"><![CDATA[You breathe deeply of the cool and fragrant air several times, and with each breath, you feel more refreshed.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="2:45" end="2:54"><![CDATA[Soon, you come upon the brook.  It's clear and clean as it tumbles over the rocks and some fallen logs.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="2:55" end="2:58"><![CDATA[You follow the path along the brook for a ways. ]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="2:59" end="3:07"><![CDATA[The path takes you out into a sunlit clearing where you discover a small but picturesque waterfall.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="3:08" end="3:10"><![CDATA[There's a rainbow in the mist.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="3:13" end="3:22"><![CDATA[You find a comfortable place to sit for a while; a perfect spot where you can feel completely relaxed.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="3:25" end="3:35"><![CDATA[You feel good, as you allow yourself to just enjoy the warmth and solitude of this peaceful place.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="3:38" end="3:40"><![CDATA[It's now time to return.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="3:41" end="3:56"><![CDATA[You walk back down the path, through the cool trees, out into the sun-drenched overgrown garden, one last smell of the flowers, and out the creaky gate.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="3:58" end="4:03"><![CDATA[You leave this secret retreat, for now, and return down the country road.]]></Caption>
								<Caption start="4:04" end="4:12"><![CDATA[Then, back to the room, however, you know that you may visit this place whenever you wish.]]></Caption>
							</Content>
						</Content>
					</ExerciseCategory>
			
					<ExerciseCategory name="ridCategory" child_weight="50.0" displayName="RID" child_helpsWithSymptoms="reexperiencing" child_variable_tooltype="the RID tool" child_ui="SimpleExerciseController">
						<Content name="rid" title="RID Tool" displayName="RID Tool" backButton="RID" ui="SimpleExerciseIntroController" >
							<![CDATA[
							<div style="font-size:48pt;font-weight:bold;text-align:center;">RID</div>
							The RID Tool is for times when you have been triggered by a reminder of a past trauma. You will be led through three steps to manage your distress.
							]]>
							<Content name="@help" displayName="RID Tool">
								<![CDATA[
								<p>
								When you're triggered or reminded of terrible things that have happened, your mind not only believes that you're in danger, your mind and your body act like you're right back in the traumatic situation.  These lightning fast, automatic reactions are helpful at the time of the actual event because they keep you safe in dangerous situations.  But now your automatic reactions to triggers are no longer helpful because in the ‘here and now' you're not in any actual danger.
								</p>
								<p>
								You use the RID tool to stay focused and cope with your triggers.  Remember, triggers confuse your brain and your body into thinking that you're back in the original situation.  You must clear away that confusion in order to manage your responses. 
								</p>
								<p>
								RID has three steps: The first step, the R in RID, is to Relax or calm yourself.   The second step, the I in RID, is to Identify what's triggering you and how it's different from your original trauma.  And the third step, the D in RID, is to Decide how to respond to the trigger. Doing these three things when you're triggered can be very helpful.
								</p>
								]]>
							</Content>
							<Content name="@next" displayName="Begin" title="RID: Relax" backButton="Relax" ui="RIDRelaxController">
								<![CDATA[
								<div style="font-size:48pt;font-weight:bold;text-align:center;"><span style="color:red;">R</span>ID</div>
								<div style="font-size:120%;text-align:center;">Relax</div>
								<hr/>
								Take 30 seconds to <b>Relax</b> by breathing in and out slowly. As you breathe in think the word "let," and as you breathe out think "go."
								]]>
								<Content name="@next" displayName="Go On" title="RID: Identify" backButton="Identify" ui="RIDSubsequentController" >
									<![CDATA[
									<div style="font-size:48pt;font-weight:bold;text-align:center;">R<span style="color:red;">I</span>D</div>
									<div style="font-size:120%;text-align:center;">Identify the Trigger</div>
									<hr/>
									<p>
										Go back over the last few minutes or hours and <b>Identify</b> what reminder of your trauma you encountered. Triggers can be internal, like thoughts or memories, or external, like conversations or situations or things we encounter in the world (e.g., a particular person or place).  Figuring out what triggered you can be tricky sometimes.  Do not worry if you cannot identify the trigger, just focus on relaxing and talking yourself down.
									</p>
									<p>
										Once you identify the trigger if you can, it is important to remind yourself that it is just a reminder and not the actual trauma happening again, despite how your mind and body may be reacting.  Really notice how the current trigger is different from your trauma.  Remind yourself of those differences again and again.
			                        </p>
									<p>
			                            Go on to fill in your triggers on the next screen.
			                        </p>
									]]>
			                        <Content name="@next" displayName="Go On" title="RID: Identify" backButton="Identify" ui="RIDSubsequentController" >
			                            <![CDATA[
			                                <div style="font-size:48pt;font-weight:bold;text-align:center;">R<span style="color:red;">I</span>D</div>
			                                <div style="font-size:120%;text-align:center;">Identify the Trigger</div>
			                                <hr/>
			                            ]]>
			                            <Content name="input1" exampleText="e.g., 'Drove under a bridge.">
			                                What triggered you?
			                            </Content>
			                            <Content name="input2" exampleText="e.g., 'In Australia, not Iraq. Civilians on the highway.  Driving my own car.'">
			                                How is your current situation different from the traumatic experience?
			                            </Content>
			                            
			                            <Content name="@next" displayName="Go On" title="RID: Decide" backButton="Decide" ui="RIDSubsequentController" >
			                                <![CDATA[
			                                <div style="font-size:48pt;font-weight:bold;text-align:center;">RI<span style="color:red;">D</span></div>
			                                <div style="font-size:120%;text-align:center;">Decide What to Do Now</div>
			                                <hr/>
			                                <p>
			                                	The final step is to <b>Decide</b> what to do now. If you feel stressed now, you can try to decrease the trigger's power by deciding to stay in the situation - i.e. not try to avoid or escape that trigger. Most people quickly realise that they can handle it and that their stress will actually go down the longer they stick it out. If the trigger made you very angry, your best bet is to decide to take a time out.  If you are in danger of hurting yourself or others, seek support and don't take any chances.
			                                </p>
			                                <p>
			                                    Go on to fill in your decision on the next screen.
			                                </p>
			                                ]]>
			                                <Content name="@next" displayName="Go On" title="RID: Decide" backButton="Decide" ui="RIDSubsequentController" >
			                                    <![CDATA[
			                                        <div style="font-size:48pt;font-weight:bold;text-align:center;">RI<span style="color:red;">D</span></div>
			                                        <div style="font-size:120%;text-align:center;">Decide What to Do Now</div>
			                                        <hr/>
			                                    ]]>
			                                    <Content name="input3" exampleText="e.g., 'Go back a few times and drive under the bridge until it doesn't bother me as much.'">
			                                        What will you decide to do?
			                                    </Content>
			                                    <Content name="@next" displayName="Finish" title="RID Summary" backButton="Summary" ui="SimpleExerciseController" >
			                                        <![CDATA[
			                                        <p>How you were triggered:</p>
			                                        <ul><li style="font-weight:bold;">${input1}</li></ul>
			                                        <p>How your current situation is different from the traumatic experience:</p>
			                                        <ul><li style="font-weight:bold;">${input2}</li></ul>
			                                        <p>You decided:</p>
			                                        <ul><li style="font-weight:bold;">${input3}</li></ul>
			                                        ]]>
			                                    </Content>
			                                </Content>
			                            </Content>
			                        </Content>
								</Content>
							</Content>
						</Content>
					</ExerciseCategory>
			
					<ExerciseCategory name="changePerspective" child_weight="0.3" categoryLevelFavorite="YES" displayName="Change Perspective" child_help="changePerspectiveHelp" child_variable_tooltype="challenging your thoughts" child_title="Change Perspective" child_ui="SimpleExerciseController" child_image="thinker.jpg">
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="hopeless anxiety anger sleep"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this more helpful thought:
							<div><b>This is a hassle, not a horror.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="reexperiencing avoidance isolation hopeless anxiety anger"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>I have been through many hard things in my life and survived.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="reexperiencing avoidance isolation hopeless anxiety anger sleep"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>I can tolerate this.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="sleep"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>I will survive even if I don't sleep at all tonight.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="reexperiencing"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>This situation is different than what happened to me and I'm going to be fine.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="reexperiencing dissociation"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>I am right here, right now.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="reexperiencing avoidance anxiety hopeless anger"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>This may seem hard now, but it will get easier and easier over time.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="avoidance isolation anxiety"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>When this is over, I'll be glad I did it.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="avoidance isolation hopeless anxiety"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>I've done this before, so I know I can do it again.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="reexperiencing avoidance anxiety"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>I know I'm in a safe place, even though my mind is telling me something else.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="reexperiencing dissociation hopeless anxiety"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>I can feel my heart beating and my feet on the floor.  I am alive and okay.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="reexperiencing avoidance hopeless anxiety anger"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>I've been through worse before and made it through safely.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="reexperiencing"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>My body is reacting to a memory.  Right now I am safe.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="reexperiencing avoidance isolation hopeless anxiety anger"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>I don't have to feel comfortable all the time.  That just proves I am human.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="reexperiencing avoidance isolation hopeless anxiety anger"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>This emotion will come and go.  I will feel differently in twenty minutes.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="dissociation hopeless anxiety anger"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>I am able to respond effectively. I have skills to handle this situation.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="reexperiencing avoidance isolation hopeless anxiety anger"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>I have been through this before and been just fine.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="reexperiencing avoidance isolation hopeless anxiety anger"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>This is another challenge that I will figure out and face.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="reexperiencing avoidance isolation hopeless anxiety anger"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>These emotions are telling me something.  They won't hurt me.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="avoidance isolation hopeless anxiety anger"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>I am human.  I can make mistakes. No one is perfect.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="reexperiencing avoidance isolation anxiety anger"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>I am able to protect myself.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="reexperiencing avoidance anxiety"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>Slow down.  I know there is more than one choice I can make.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="reexperiencing avoidance isolation hopeless anxiety"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>I can ask others for help.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="reexperiencing avoidance anxiety"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>I have made the right decision before.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="reexperiencing avoidance isolation dissociation hopeless anxiety anger"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>My thoughts are just thoughts; they're not always right. Don't believe everything you think.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="reexperiencing avoidance isolation dissociation anxiety anger"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>I am strong.  I am safe now.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="reexperiencing avoidance dissociation hopeless anxiety anger"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>This feeling will pass.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="reexperiencing avoidance dissociation hopeless anxiety anger"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>I will not feel this way forever.  I have felt differently before and will feel differently soon.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="reexperiencing avoidance isolation dissociation anxiety anger"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>I am in a safe place.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="reexperiencing avoidance hopeless anxiety anger"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>The emotions I feel right now are giving me information about how I feel but they're not necessarily based on facts.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="reexperiencing avoidance hopeless anxiety anger"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>If I don't fight my emotions, they will go down on their own.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="isolation hopeless anxiety"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>I am a decent person.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="reexperiencing avoidance isolation hopeless anxiety anger"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>It is okay if it takes me time to figure this out.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="avoidance isolation hopeless anxiety"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>There is always time to learn.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="avoidance isolation anxiety"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>Learning will give me more options in the future.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="reexperiencing avoidance isolation hopeless anxiety anger"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>There are times when I will fall back into old patterns.  I just need to catch myself and get back on track with what's effective.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="avoidance hopeless anxiety"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>It's not always like this. There are times I have felt pretty amazing, too.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="hopeless anxiety"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>I know that I deserve love.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="avoidance hopeless anxiety"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>I am my own unique person: special, talented, and worthwhile.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="hopeless anxiety anger sleep"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>One night of poor sleep is not the end of the world.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="sleep"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>This tossing and turning at night will pass.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="reexperiencing sleep"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>Nightmares are disturbing, but they're not real. I am safe.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="sleep"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>Although it feels like I will never get a good night's sleep, I have in the past and I will in the future.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content helpsWithSymptoms="sleep"><![CDATA[
							Changing the way you think can change the way you feel.  Concentrate on this functional thought:
							<div><b>Although I am anticipating a poor night's sleep, it could be fine... I have slept well before.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
					</ExerciseCategory>
			
					<ExerciseCategory name="grounding" child_weight="1.0" displayName="Grounding" child_title="Grounding" child_variable_tooltype="doing a grounding exercise" child_help="groundingHelp" categoryLevelFavorite="YES" child_helpsWithSymptoms="reexperiencing dissociation anxiety" child_ui="SimpleExerciseController" child_image="grounding.jpg">
						<Content displayName="Feel feet on floor"><![CDATA[
							Focus all of your attention on your feet. Feel the floor 
under them.

						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Texture of a Pebble"><![CDATA[
							Focus all of your attention on the feel of a pebble or coin in your hand.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Breathing"><![CDATA[
							Sit quietly and focus all of your attention on your in-breath and then your out-breath.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="The Space Around You--Colours"><![CDATA[
							Look around and focus your attention on the colours around you, noticing as many colours as you can.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="The Space Around You--Smells"><![CDATA[
							Focus all of your attention on the smells in your environment.  
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="The Space Around You--Sounds"><![CDATA[
							Focus on and listen carefully to the many sounds in your environment.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="The Space Around You--Temperature"><![CDATA[
							Focus all of your attention of the temperature of the air on your skin.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Eating"><![CDATA[
							While you are eating, focus all of your attention on the sensations of the food in your mouth while you chew very slowly.  
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Brushing your teeth"><![CDATA[
							Brush your teeth and focus your attention on all of the sensations, tastes, and smells of this activity.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Walking"><![CDATA[
							Walk slowly, focusing your attention on what it feels like to take each step.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Object"><![CDATA[
							Pick up any small object off the ground and focus all of your attention on the texture of the object and the feel of it in your hand.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Pet an animal"><![CDATA[
							Pet an animal that is quiet and calm.  Focus all of your attention on the sensations on your hand.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Attach yourself to the earth"><![CDATA[
							With your feet shoulder width apart, close your eyes and imagine that you are growing roots into the earth, making you strong and stable.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Ice Cube"><![CDATA[
							Grab an ice cube and focus all of your attention on the sensations that go with it, cold, wet, and tingling.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Name what you see"><![CDATA[
							Look around you and name what you see.  Start with large objects, then move to smaller and smaller objects.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Focus on touch"><![CDATA[
							Rub your hands together, clap your hands.  Focus all of your attention on the feelings and sounds that you experience.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Reorientation"><![CDATA[
							Remind yourself where you are, what today's date is, when were you born, and what you did yesterday.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Call a friend"><![CDATA[
							Call a friend and discuss some activity you did together recently.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Past success"><![CDATA[
							Remember what you did to successfully get past a previous distressing experience.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Baby steps"><![CDATA[
							Ask yourself and answer: What would be a small sign that things are getting a little better?
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Suck on a peppermint"><![CDATA[
							Slowly suck on a mint and describe the taste and your reaction in detail to yourself.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Stamp your feet on the ground"><![CDATA[
							Stamp your feet on the ground. Feel the force.  Hear the sounds.  Notice.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Feel your clothes on your skin"><![CDATA[
							Pay attention to the sensation of your clothes touching your skin.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Feel your hands"><![CDATA[
							Put your hands together and notice the sensations of the skin-on-skin contact.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Hear Others"><![CDATA[
							Tune into the voices of others around you. Only pay attention to the sounds of others' voices.
						]]></Content>
					</ExerciseCategory>
			
					<ExerciseCategory name="planToReduceIsolationCategory" displayName="Make a Plan to Reduce Isolation" child_variable_tooltype="making a plan to reduce isolation" child_help="reduceIsolationHelp" child_ui="SimpleExerciseController">
						<Content name="planToReduceIsolation" helpsWithSymptoms="isolation hopeless anxiety" weight="10.0" displayName="Reduce Isolation" title="Reduce Isolation" backButton="Intro" ui="SimpleExerciseIntroController">
							<![CDATA[
							When you're feeling isolated, making a plan to do an activity with a friend can help.  Follow the steps in the next screen
							to make a place for meeting up later with a friend or family member.
							]]>
							<Content name="@next" displayName="Make my plan" title="Make A Plan" backButton="Plan" ui="PlanController">
								<Content name="@inline">
                                    <![CDATA[
									Select one or more people you can spend time with. Think about inviting friends, family members, co-workers, people from your neighborhood or spiritual community, people through your loved one's unit or installation, people you want to get to know better, etc.:
                                    ]]>
								</Content>
								<Content name="@inline" ui="ChosenContactListViewController" variableKey="socialActivitySummaryContactList" pick="true" multi="true"/>
								<Content name="@inline">
									Select an activity to do with this person or these people:
								</Content>
								<Content name="@activities" title="Select Activity" ui="ContentListViewController" selectOnly="true" selectionVariable="socialActivity">
									<Content displayName="Go for a walk" />
									<Content displayName="Go fishing" />
									<Content displayName="Have tea or coffee at home" />
									<Content displayName="Go out for tea or coffee" />
									<Content displayName="Have a meal at home" />
									<Content displayName="Go out for a meal" />
									<Content displayName="Go to a museum or gallery" />
									<Content displayName="Go to a musical, dance or other performance" />
									<Content displayName="Go to the park" />
									<Content displayName="Have a picnic" />
									<Content displayName="Go to the gym" />
									<Content displayName="Go to the beach" />
									<Content displayName="Go to a lake" />
									<Content displayName="Go out in a boat or canoe" />
									<Content displayName="Go for a drive" />
									<Content displayName="Go for a bike ride" />
									<Content displayName="Golf" />
									<Content displayName="Play tennis" />
									<Content displayName="Go for a run" />
									<Content displayName="Take your dog(s) out" />
									<Content displayName="Take a day trip out of town" />
									<Content displayName="Go to the movies" />
									<Content displayName="Go shopping" />
									<Content displayName="Go window shopping" />
									<Content displayName="Kick a footy with a friend" />
									<Content displayName="Play cards" />
									<Content displayName="Play chess or another board/strategy game" />
									<Content displayName="Play basketball" />
									<Content displayName="Sit and talk" />
									<Content displayName="Have a snack and talk" />
									<Content displayName="Work on a project together" />
									<Content displayName="Run errands together" />
									<Content displayName="Go to a party or gathering" />
									<Content displayName="Go to a yoga class" />
									<Content displayName="Go to a meditation class" />
									<Content displayName="Take kids to the playground" />
								</Content>
								<Content name="@next" displayName="Next" title="Make It Happen" newToolPrompt="@none" backButton="Plan" ui="ScheduleItController"
									buttongrid_cellsPerRow="1" buttongrid_cellMarginY="10" buttongrid_outerMarginY="10" buttongrid_outerMarginX="10" buttongrid_buttonjust="left"
									buttonTheme="theme_big_button">
									<![CDATA[
										You've chosen to <b>${socialActivitySummary}</b>.  You can invite people now, or add this activity to your calendar to do later.
									]]>
								</Content>
							</Content>
						</Content>
					</ExerciseCategory>
			
					<ExerciseCategory name="timeout" child_weight="1.0" displayName="Take a Time Out" title="Take a Time Out" child_helpsWithSymptoms="anger" child_variable_tooltype="taking a time out" ui="CategoryIntroController" child_ui="TimeoutController" child_help="timeOutHelp" categoryLevelFavorite="YES" child_image="time_out.jpg" child_title="Time Out" child_timeoutDuration="5">
						Sometimes the most effective thing to do is take time out. This is especially helpful if your anger is escalating and you might do something hurtful or with consequences that you'd later regret. The goal is to avoid making a hard situation worse. 
						<Content name="takeWalk" displayName="Take a walk"><![CDATA[
							Take a walk.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Do some deep breathing for 5 minutes or more "><![CDATA[
							Do some deep breathing for 5 minutes or more.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Exercise (bike, hike, lift weights, swim, run) "><![CDATA[
							Exercise (bike, hike, lift weights, swim, run, walk).
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Do some gardening"><![CDATA[
							Do some gardening.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Tell yourself something empowering, like 'I can handle this without losing my temper.'"><![CDATA[
							Tell yourself something empowering, like "I can handle this without losing my temper."
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Draw or paint  "><![CDATA[
							Draw or paint.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Phone a friend or loved one for support "><![CDATA[
							Phone a friend or loved one for support and fresh perspectives.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Phone your counsellor for support "><![CDATA[
							Phone your counsellor for support.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Stretch and take slow, deep breaths"><![CDATA[
							Stretch and take slow, deep breaths.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Remind yourself that you can cope with this. "><![CDATA[
							Remind yourself that you can cope with this.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Meditate "><![CDATA[
							Meditate.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Pray "><![CDATA[
							Pray.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Think of how someone you trust would advise you."><![CDATA[
							Think of how someone you trust would advise you. What would they tell you to do? 
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Spend time with a pet."><![CDATA[
							Spend time with a pet.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Take a shower or a bath to relax."><![CDATA[
							Take a shower or bath to relax.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Think about how you want to be an example to others in your life- children, etc."><![CDATA[
							Think about how you can be an example to children and others in your life right now.
						]]></Content>
					</ExerciseCategory>
			
					<ExerciseCategory name="helpSleeping" child_weight="1.0" displayName="Help Falling Asleep" categoryLevelFavorite="YES" child_title="Help Falling Asleep" child_help="sleepHelp" child_variable_tooltype="getting tips for falling asleep" child_helpsWithSymptoms="sleep" child_ui="SimpleExerciseController" child_image="insomnia.jpg">
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Tip for Falling Asleep: Only go to bed when you are sleepy.
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Tip for Falling Asleep: If you are in bed for 20 minutes and are still not asleep, get up and do something else (without exposing yourself to bright light or a computer/phone/TV screen).
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Tip for Falling Asleep: Listen to relaxing music.
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Tip for Falling Asleep: Read something soothing.
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Tip for Falling Asleep: Have a cup of decaffeinated tea.
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Tip for Falling Asleep: Have a cup of warm milk.
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Tip for Falling Asleep: Take some slow, deep breaths through your nose-- do this for 10 minutes. You can use the breathing tool on this app if you would like.
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Tip for Falling Asleep: Have a light snack if you are hungry- try something low in sugar and alcohol-free.
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Tip for Falling Asleep: Make sure the room is cool.
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Tip for Falling Asleep: Try wearing earplugs if there is noise in your environment.
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Tip for Falling Asleep: If there is light in your environment, try a eye mask.
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Tip for Falling Asleep: Make sure the room is dark.
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Tip for Falling Asleep: Try taking a warm bath an hour or two before bed.
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Tip for Falling Asleep: Make sure you are comfortable and clothing is not constraining.
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Tip for Falling Asleep: Avoid watching the clock.
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Tip for Falling Asleep: Let your mind wander. Don't focus too much on the process of falling asleep.
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Tip for Falling Asleep: If you find yourself worrying, get up and write your worries down, then let them go.
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Tip for Falling Asleep: Picture a calming safe place: picture yourself by a river, a lake, or in a meadow. Imagine the scene, the sights and sounds and smells, as you drift off. You can use the positive imagery tool on this app if you would like.
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Tip for Falling Asleep: Feel all the muscles of your body relax, as if sinking into the mattress. You can use the progressive muscle relaxation tool on this app if you would like.
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Tip for Falling Asleep: Avoid nicotine, caffeine, and alcohol in the evenings.
							]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Tip for Falling Asleep: Avoid too much salt in your food.  This can cause you to wake-up thirsty throughout the night.
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Tip for Falling Asleep: Turn off the TV and computer 30 minutes before bedtime. 
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Tip for Falling Asleep: Develop a relaxing bedtime routine.
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Tip for Falling Asleep: Get up and have a glass of water.
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Tip for Falling Asleep: Ensure that your sheets are clean and that your pillow and mattress are comfortable and supportive.
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Tip for Falling Asleep: Try not to worry about falling asleep; just allow it to happen.
						]]></Content>
					</ExerciseCategory>
			
					<ExerciseCategory name="pleasantEvents" child_weight="1.0" displayName="Pleasant Events" child_title="Pleasant Events" child_helpsWithSymptoms="hopeless isolation anxiety" child_variable_tooltype="scheduling pleasant events" child_ui="SimpleExerciseController" child_displayName="Pleasant Events" child_help="pleasantHelp" child_image="pleasant.jpg" categoryLevelFavorite="YES">
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Take a relaxing bath.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Plan a trip.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Go to the movies.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Go for a walk.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Go for a run.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Watch funny videos.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Watch a movie.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Read a magazine.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Read a book.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Spend time with a friend.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Remember a fun vacation.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Eat something delicious.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Practice yoga.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Take care of projects around the house.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Remember someone being kind to you.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Put on clothes that makes you feel good.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Practice a martial art.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Garden.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Go for a swim.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Exercise.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Go to a party.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Play a sport.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Phone a friend.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Phone a family member.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Go camping.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Sing around the house.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Buy yourself flowers.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Pray.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Go to church/temple/mosque.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Go to the beach.</b></div>
						]]></Content>

						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Go fishing.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Go bike riding.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Paint or draw.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Go for a drive.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Cook dinner for someone.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Bake something.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Play a musical instrument.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Do arts and crafts.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Make a gift for someone.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Buy yourself music.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Go to a bookshop.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Go hiking.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Watch sports on TV.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Write a poem or story.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Buy clothes.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Go sightseeing.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Get a manicure/pedicure.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Play tennis.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Play golf.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Watch children play.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Go to a live show or play.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Go see live music.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Watch TV.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Go out to dinner.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Cook for yourself.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Sew, knit, or crochet.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Join a book club.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Go to a coffee shop to read and have coffee/tea.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Have coffee and read the paper.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Buy someone a gift.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Complete a task.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Go watch horse racing or auto racing.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Take photographs.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Read the paper.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Write a letter.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Play with animals.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Dance.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Go for a picnic.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Meditate.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Take a trip to the mountains.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Go to the ocean/lake/river.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Play cards.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Do a puzzle.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Play sudoku.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Do a crossword puzzle.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Play pool.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Buy yourself a small gift.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Talk on the phone.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Go to a museum.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Light candles.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Listen to the radio.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Get a massage.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Take a sauna/spa</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>List 5 things you like about yourself.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Buy yourself a book.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Go bowling.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Kick a footy.</b></div>
						]]></Content>						
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Take a class (language, dance).</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Do woodworking.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Volunteer at a soup kitchen.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Volunteer at an animal shelter.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Change negative moods by doing something pleasant:
							<div><b>Think about someone you love.</b></div>
						]]></Content>
					</ExerciseCategory>
			
					<ExerciseCategory name="seekSupportCategory" child_weight="1.0" displayName="Seek Support" child_variable_tooltype="seeking support" child_helpsWithSymptoms="reexperiencing avoidance isolation dissociation hopeless anxiety anger" child_help="seekSupportHelp" child_ui="SimpleExerciseController">
						<Content name="seekSupport" displayName="Seek Support" ui="BaseExerciseController" backButton="Seek Support" title="Seek Support" theme="theme_default">
                            <Content name="@inline">For any crisis, including medical emergencies:</Content>
                            <Content name="@inline" ui="ContentListViewController">
                                <Content displayName="Call 000" href="tel:000"/>
                            </Content>
                            <Content name="@inline"><![CDATA[Veterans and Veterans Families Counselling Service:]]></Content>
                            <Content name="@inline" ui="ContentListViewController">
                                <Content displayName="Call 1800-011-046" href="tel:1800-011-046"/>
                            </Content>
                            <Content name="@inline" predicate="dae.preferredContactSet">
                                <Content name="@inline">Your preferred mental health professional:</Content>
                                <Content name="@inline" ui="ChosenContactListViewController" show="preferredOnly"/>
                            </Content>
                            <Content name="@inline" predicate="(dae.contactsCount>0 &amp;&amp; !dae.preferredContactSet) || dae.contactsCount>1">
                                <Content name="@inline">Your support contacts:</Content>
                                <Content name="@inline" ui="ChosenContactListViewController" show="nonPreferredOnly"/>
                            </Content>
                            <Content name="@inline" predicate="(dae.contactsCount==0) || !dae.contactsCount">
                                Your don't have any support contacts selected.  Visit 'Setup' to select your support contacts.
                                <Content name="@button" displayName="Go to Setup" ref="setup" refAction="pop"/>
                            </Content>
						</Content>
					</ExerciseCategory>
			
					<ExerciseCategory name="distract" child_weight="1.0" displayName="Distract from Intense Emotions" child_title="Distract Yourself" child_variable_tooltype="distracting yourself from intense emotion" child_helpsWithSymptoms="reexperiencing hopeless anxiety anger" child_ui="SimpleExerciseController" child_help="distractHelp" categoryLevelFavorite="YES" child_image="butterfly.jpg">
						<Content displayName="Woodworking"><![CDATA[
							Brainstorm, start, or continue with a project, working with your hands.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Watch a sports game"><![CDATA[
							Turn on your favorite sporting event and let yourself get into it.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Go for a walk around the block"><![CDATA[
							Moving your legs, even just walking around the block, helps to foster a different perspective.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Play with children."><![CDATA[
							Remember those little ones in your family that just crack you up? Go spend time with them.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Go for a run."><![CDATA[
							Go for a run to raise your heart rate, clear your mind, and release some tension in your muscles.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Read favourite comic book"><![CDATA[
							Laughing and going into another world would be good for you.  Take a load off and read a comic book.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Watch a funny movie"><![CDATA[
							It's hard to be upset when watching your favourite comedy movie.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Cook a meal and eat it"><![CDATA[
							Cook your favourite meal and savour every bite. 
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Take a mental holiday"><![CDATA[
							Allow your mind to take a holiday from your problems.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Chop wood"><![CDATA[
							Get some of that energy out by chopping wood and then relax in front of the fireplace.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Facebook"><![CDATA[
							Get on Facebook and connect with your friends virtually.  What are other people up to these days?
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Draw a picture"><![CDATA[
							Draw a picture and be creative!
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Mold clay"><![CDATA[
							Moulding clay allows your hands to create a masterpiece or to just mix the colours.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Write poetry"><![CDATA[
							Express yourself with your poetic words.  Put it down on paper.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Do a jigsaw puzzle"><![CDATA[
							Worried you are falling to pieces?  Get a puzzle and have fun putting the pieces together.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Do Sudoko/crossword"><![CDATA[
							Play sudoku or do a crossword.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Clean your room"><![CDATA[
							Clean and straighten up your surroundings.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Walk your dog"><![CDATA[
							Walk your dog... he needs a break too.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Rubik's cube"><![CDATA[
							Remember Rubik's cube?!  Looks simple, yet it's mystifying.  Get busy with your hands and mind.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Go shopping"><![CDATA[
							See what's new at the mall or your favourite shopping center. You can even shop around online!
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Phone a friend"><![CDATA[
							Pick up the phone and see what your friends are up to.  Connecting with them will distract you from your own mind.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Email a distant friend"><![CDATA[
							There's no better time to catch up with a friend via e-mail.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Do a home project"><![CDATA[
							Work on that project you have been saving for a rainy day.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Sing along to the radio"><![CDATA[
							Turn on your radio and sing in the car.  Or just blast it at home and belt it out.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Do something for someone else"><![CDATA[
							Feel better about yourself by doing something nice for someone else.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Plan your next vacation"><![CDATA[
							Nothing like having a trip to look forward to in the future.  Get started planning a holiday.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Scribble/doodle on paper"><![CDATA[
							Just pick up a pen and put it down on the paper.  See what you create.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Alphabetise your bookcase/spice rack"><![CDATA[
							Use your mind to organise your books or spice rack. It can be nice to have some order when your emotions feel chaotic!
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Count to 100"><![CDATA[
							Counting to 10 not enough to cool you down?  Try higher... say, 100?
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Make as many words out of your full name as possible"><![CDATA[
							Word scramble your full name and see how many words you can make out of it!
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Go fishing"><![CDATA[
							Catch some fish at the local beach, lake or creek.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Volunteer"><![CDATA[
							Volunteer and do something nice for someone else. It will make you feel good!
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Go to a museum"><![CDATA[
							Be inspired by the works of others at a museum.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Ask someone to tell you a funny story"><![CDATA[
							Ask someone to tell you a funny story. There's nothing like hearing the adventures of others.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Play pool"><![CDATA[
							Play some pool, sink them, and have fun!
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Watch your favourite television show"><![CDATA[
							Watch some of your favourite TV shows. 
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Phone  a long distance friend"><![CDATA[
							Time to check in with a friend.  Who haven't you talked to in awhile?
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Make funny faces in the mirror"><![CDATA[
							Crack yourself up by making funny faces in the mirror.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Think about the future"><![CDATA[
							Imagine those times in your life you have been excited about: finishing study, falling in love, going on your next adventure.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Write thank you cards"><![CDATA[
							Express gratitude and write to others to let them know you appreciate them thinking of you.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Take a nap"><![CDATA[
							Take a break and let yourself just sleep and recharge for a few minutes.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Put your troubles in an imaginary shoebox on the shelf for awhile"><![CDATA[
							Imagine packing your troubles up and storing them away - you can come back to them later.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="YouTube"><![CDATA[
							Find something funny to laugh at on YouTube.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Go to a friend's house"><![CDATA[
							Go somewhere else, like a friend's house, to hang out.
						]]></Content>
					</ExerciseCategory>
			
					<ExerciseCategory name="soothYourself" child_weight="10.0" displayName="Soothe Yourself" child_title="Sooth Yourself" child_variable_tooltype="soothing yourself" child_helpsWithSymptoms="reexperiencing dissociation hopeless anxiety sleep" child_help="sootheHelp" child_ui="SimpleExerciseController" >
							<Content name="soothWithMyPictures" displayName="Soothing Pictures" title="Soothing Pictures" ui="SoothingPictureController">
                                <Content name="@inline" predicate="dae.platform=='android'">
                                    Look at a picture that is meaningful or soothing to you.  (Tap on the picture to zoom in.)
                                </Content>
                                <Content name="@inline" predicate="dae.platform=='iphone'">
                                    Look at a picture that is meaningful or soothing to you.  (Tap on the plus sign to zoom in.)
                                </Content>
							</Content>
							<Content name="soothWithMyAudio" displayName="Soothing Audio" title="Soothing Audio" ui="SoothingAudioController" image="tea.jpg">
								Listening to soothing songs or audio clips can help.  Put in headphones or go to a private place and tap the button to play the audio.
							</Content>
			<!--
						<Content displayName="Wash your hands"><![CDATA[
							Soothe yourself by washing your hands slowly with warm water.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Pet your animal"><![CDATA[
							Spend time with your pet and let them know you love them.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Put on some lotion"><![CDATA[
							Put on lotion and pay attention to the way this feels. Take care of your body.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Look at photos of people you love"><![CDATA[
							Look at photos of people you love. Take in the soothing images.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Play your favourite playlist"><![CDATA[
							Listen to your favourite music. 
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Hold your child and/or a loved one's hand"><![CDATA[
							Receive and give comfort to a close one.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Rabbit's foot"><![CDATA[
							Feel something soft, like a rabbit's foot, with your hands.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Sit by fireplace"><![CDATA[
							Feel the warmth on your skin and look at the color of the flames in the fireplace.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Exercise"><![CDATA[
							Move your body around and feel healthier.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Be in nature"><![CDATA[
							Allow the beauty of nature to be around you.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Gardening"><![CDATA[
							Try some gardening and GROW outside.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Plan a trip"><![CDATA[
							Time to think ahead to your next vacation/trip.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Favorite meal"><![CDATA[
							Treat yourself to that special favourite meal.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Baking cookies"><![CDATA[
							Enjoy the smell of cookies baking.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Voicemail from a friend"><![CDATA[
							Hear the words of a close friend by listening to a saved voicemail.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Journaling"><![CDATA[
							Put your thoughts down on paper for yourself.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Clean sheets"><![CDATA[
							Smell the clean scent of new sheets and let yourself spread out.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Sun on your skin"><![CDATA[
							Sit outside and feel the sun beat down on you.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Dessert"><![CDATA[
							Enjoy every bite of a favourite dessert.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Warm shower"><![CDATA[
							Take a shower and feel the water on your skin and relax.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Get a massage"><![CDATA[
							Release the tension in your muscles by having someone massage it away.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Hug someone"><![CDATA[
							Find comfort in someone's arms.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Stretch/do yoga"><![CDATA[
							Release the tension by stretching or doing yoga.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Nap"><![CDATA[
							Allow your body to rest and take a nap.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Pray"><![CDATA[
							Talk to a higher power.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Read the bible/etc"><![CDATA[
							Read a document that feels profound  to you and find guidance in the words of others.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Soft sweater"><![CDATA[
							Wear clothes that feel comfortable on your body.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Flower arrangement"><![CDATA[
							It's time to smell the roses and make a flower arrangement.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Call therapist"><![CDATA[
							Phone your therapist to ask for cheerleadings and support.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Something you are proud of"><![CDATA[
							Remember the skills you do have and what you do well.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="A time you felt better"><![CDATA[
							Notice the good moments and give them weight.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Notice your breath"><![CDATA[
							Take in a deep breath and exhale slowly .
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Pleasant sound"><![CDATA[
							Ring a bell
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Read a favourite book"><![CDATA[
							Pull that favourite book off your shelf and jump into it.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Read a magazine."><![CDATA[
							Thumb through a magazine or two.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Brainstorming life appreciation"><![CDATA[
							Write a gratitude list
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Self care"><![CDATA[
							Write yourself an "I love you" letter
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Jacuzzi"><![CDATA[
							Get in a jacuzzi and feel the hot jets.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Warm drink"><![CDATA[
							Drink a warm drink like tea, warm milk, coffee.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Create an internal safe place where you can go"><![CDATA[
							 In a time when you feel safe and secure, create a room or a garden or any safe area inside yourself where you can retreat to and get away from external stresses. Add as many detials as you can to make it real for you.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Positive pics/words from magazine"><![CDATA[
							Go through magazines and cut out pictures and words that make you feel good about yourself
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Spend time with family"><![CDATA[
							Go on an outing with your granchild.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Feeling of problem solving"><![CDATA[
							Notice what it will feel like once you have solved a problem.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Progressive Muscle Relaxation"><![CDATA[
							Intentionally tense your muscles and then release them and notice the difference.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Change clothes"><![CDATA[
							Wear clothes that feel comfortable on your body.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Positive statements"><![CDATA[
							Make sure to balance the negatives with positive comments.
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Blanket"><![CDATA[
							Wrap yourself in your favourite blanket
						]]></Content>
						<Content displayName="Pictures from a positive event"><![CDATA[
							Go through pictures that catalog the good times.
						]]></Content>
			-->			
					</ExerciseCategory>
			
					<ExerciseCategory name="quotes" child_weight="0.1" displayName="Inspiring Quotes" child_title="Inspiring Quotes" categoryLevelFavorite="YES" child_variable_tooltype="reading inspiring quotes" child_helpsWithSymptoms="reexperiencing avoidance isolation dissociation hopeless anxiety sleep" child_help="quotesHelp" child_ui="SimpleExerciseController" child_image="summit.jpg">
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Although the world is full of suffering, it is full also of the overcoming of it.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Helen Keller</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							You are not responsible for being down, but you are responsible for getting up.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Jesse Jackson</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							No feeling is final.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Ranier Maria Rilke</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Not to laugh, not to lament, not to judge, but to understand.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Baruch Spinoza</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							And the trouble is, if you don't risk anything, you risk even more.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Erica Jong</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Don't compromise yourself. You are all you you've got.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Janis Joplin</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							You yourself, as much as anybody in the entire universe, deserve your love and affection.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Buddha</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							...be attentive to what is arising within you, and place that above everything else... What is happening in your innermost self is worthy of your entire love; somehow you must find a way to work at it.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Ranier Maria Rilke</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Never, never, never, never, never give up.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Winston Churchill</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Watch your thoughts; they become your words. Watch your words; they become your actions. Watch your actions; they become your habits. Watch your habits; they become your character. Watch your character; it becomes your destiny.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Frank Outlaw</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Do what you can, with what you have, where you are.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Theodore Roosevelt</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Let your heart guide you. It whispers, so listen closely.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Molly Goode</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Life is never what one dreams. It is seldom what one desires, but for the vital spirit and the eager mind, the future will always hold the search for buried treasure and the possibility of high adventure.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Ellen Glasgow</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							It takes two to speak the truth—one to speak, the other to hear.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Henry David Thoreau</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							When you do a thing, do it with all your might. Put your whole soul into it. Stamp it with your personality. Be active, be energetic, be enthusiastic and faithful, and you will accomplish your object. 
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Ralph Waldo Emerson</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							The future depends on what we do in the present.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Mohandas K. Gandhi</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							If we change within, our outer life will change also.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Jean Shinoda Bolen</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Perhaps the truth depends on a walk around the lake. 
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Wallace Stevens</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							A loving heart is the truest wisdom.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Charles Dickens</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Each of us is two selves, and the great challenge of life is to try to keep that higher self in command.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Martin Luther King Jr.</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							In the time of your life, live.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;William Saroyan</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Life is not what it's supposed to be. It's what it is. The way you cope with it is what makes the difference.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Virginia Satir</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							The difference between the impossible and the possible lies in a person's determination.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Tommy Lasorda</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Remember there's no such thing as a small act of kindness. Every act creates a ripple with no logical end.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Scott Adams</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							The fact is, that to do anything in the world worth doing, we must not stand back shivering and thinking of the cold and danger, but jump in and scramble through as well as we can.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Robert Cushing</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Follow your honest convictions, and stay strong.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;William Thackeray</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Knowing yourself is the beginning of all wisdom.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Aristotle</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Your real influence is measured by your treatment of yourself.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;A. Bronson Alcott</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Energy and persistence conquer all things.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Benjamin Franklin</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Fear less, hope more, eat less, chew more, whine less, breathe more, talk less, say more, hate less, love more, and good things will be yours.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Swedish Proverb</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							I have learned that the greater part of our misery or unhappiness is determined not by our circumstance but by our disposition.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Martha Washington</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							The only journey is the journey within.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Ranier Rilke</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Every day do something that will inch you closer to a better tomorrow.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Doug Firebaugh</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							The happiest life is that which constantly exercises and educates what is best in us.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Hamerton</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							If we all did the things we are capable of, we would astound ourselves.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Thomas Edison</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Go back a little to leap further.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;John Clarke</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							I failed my way to success.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Thomas Edison</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Don't waste your life in doubts and fears: spend yourself on the work before you, well assured that the right performance of this hour's duties will be the best preparation for the hours or ages that follow it.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Ralph Waldo Emerson</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							It is the trouble that never comes that causes the loss of sleep.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Chas. Austin Bates</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							When one door of happiness closes, another opens, but often we look so long at the closed door that we do not see the one that has been opened for us.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Helen Keller</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							The more difficulties one has to encounter, within and without, the more significant and the higher in inspiration his life will be.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Horace Bushnell</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Years teach us more than books.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Berthold Auerbach</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Life is either a daring adventure or nothing. 
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Helen Keller</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							If you do not hope, you will not find what is beyond your hopes.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;St. Clement of Alexandra</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							Men's best successes come after their disappointments.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Henry Ward Beecher</div>
						]]></Content>
						<Content><![CDATA[
							The best way out is always through.
							<div style="margin:6pt;text-align:right;font-style:italic;">&mdash;Robert Frost</div>
						]]></Content>
					</ExerciseCategory>
				</Content>
				<Content name="sudsreprompt" ui="SUDSController" title="Distress Meter" backButton="Distress" fixedButtons="true" help="sudshelp" resuds="true">
				    Rate your distress again on a scale of 0 to 10. Tracking your distress will allow you to learn which tools help you the most.
				    <Content name="@next">
						<Content name="@inline" predicate="dae.resuds &gt; dae.suds" title="Distress Increased"><![CDATA[
							<p>
							Okay, it looks like after ${tooltype} you are actually more distressed. This might be good to remember for the future, since you shouldn't do things that don't work for you. But remember, some of these tools take time or practice to really work, or may only relieve certain types of problems, so don't write this one off just yet. 
							</p>
							<p>
							Since you are still stressed, maybe you should try another tool.
							</p>
							
						]]></Content>
						<Content name="@inline" predicate="dae.resuds &lt; dae.suds" title="Distress Decreased"><![CDATA[
							<p>
							Great! It looks like ${tooltype} may have brought down your distress level. Try to remember this tool. Anything that works for you once can work for you again!  
							</p>							
						]]></Content>
						<Content name="@inline" predicate="dae.resuds == dae.suds" title="Distress Unchanged" ><![CDATA[
							<p>
                            Okay, it looks like after ${tooltype} you have the same amount of distress. It's possible that this is good enough for you - after all, nothing got worse! - or maybe you were hoping for a bigger improvement. But remember, some of these tools take time or practice to really work, or may only relieve certain types of problems, so don't write this one off just yet.
							</p>
							<p>
								If you feel like it, you could try another tool now.
							</p>
						]]></Content>
						<Content name="@button" displayName="Try Another Tool" ref="exercise" refAction="clear:selectedExercise"/>
						<Content name="@button" displayName="Done" ref="manage" refAction="clear:preselectedExercise"/>
					</Content>
				</Content>
	        </Content>
	        <Content ui="NavController" displayName="Support" icon="10-medical.png">
	            <Content name="support" buttonTheme="theme_big_button" ui="ButtonGridController" title="Support" backButton="Support"
	                buttongrid_cellsPerRow="1" buttongrid_buttonjust="left">
                    <Content name="@back" icon="home_icon.png" ref="home"/>
	                <Content displayName="Get Support Right Now" icon="support_now.png" ui="ContentViewController" title="Crisis Resources" theme="theme_default" standalone="1">
	                    <Content name="@inline">For any crisis, including medical emergencies:</Content>
	                    <Content name="@inline" ui="ContentListViewController">
	                        <Content displayName="Call 000" icon="phone_icon.png" href="tel:000"/>
	                    </Content>
	                    <Content name="@inline"><![CDATA[Veterans and Veterans Families Counselling Service:]]></Content>
	                    <Content name="@inline" ui="ContentListViewController">
	                        <Content displayName="Call 1800-011-046" icon="phone_icon.png" href="tel:1800-011-046"/>
	                    </Content>
	                    <Content name="@inline" predicate="dae.preferredContactSet">
	                        <Content name="@inline">Your preferred mental health professional:</Content>
	                        <Content name="@inline" ui="ChosenContactListViewController" show="preferredOnly"/>
	                    </Content>
	                    <Content name="@inline" predicate="(dae.contactsCount>0 &amp;&amp; !dae.preferredContactSet) || dae.contactsCount>1">
	                        <Content name="@inline">Your support contacts:</Content>
	                        <Content name="@inline" ui="ChosenContactListViewController" show="nonPreferredOnly"/>
	                    </Content>
	                    <Content name="@inline" predicate="(dae.contactsCount==0) || !dae.contactsCount">
	                        Your don't have any support contacts selected.  Visit 'Setup' to select your support contacts.
			                <Content name="@button" displayName="Go to Setup" ref="setup" refAction="pop"/>
	                    </Content>
	                </Content>
	                <Content displayName="Setup My Support Network" icon="support_network.png" title="Setup Support" ui="ContentViewController" theme="theme_smaller" >
	                    <![CDATA[
	                    <p>
	                    When dealing with life stress, support from people you know and trust can be absolutely vital. Whether you are facing a small annoyance or a serious crisis, getting help from others is one of the most effective ways to make sure that you manage the situation and yourself as well as possible.
	                    </p>
	                    <p>
	                    Set up your support network by selecting trusted people from your contact list or adding them in manually. If you are currently in counselling or therapy, make sure that your mental health provider is one of the people on your support network.
	                    </p>
	                    ]]>
	                    
	                    <Content name="@button" displayName="Next" title="Support Contacts" backButton="Support Contacts" ui="ChosenContactListViewController" editing="true"
	                    	selectionIcon_file="physician.png" selectionIconEmpty_file="physician_hole.png">
	                    	Add your support contacts here.  You can also tap the icon to the right of one contact to indicate that this contact is your preferred mental health professional.
		                </Content>
	                </Content>
	                <Content name="professionalCare" displayName="Find Professional Care" title="Find Professional Care" icon="prof_care.png" ui="LayeredController" backButton="Care">
	                    <Content name="careForExServing" predicate="dae.userType=='exserving'">
	                        <![CDATA[
                            <h2>Ex-Serving Members, Veterans &amp; Family</h2>
	                        <h3>If you are in crisis:</h3>
	                        <p>
	                            Call <a href="tel:000">000</a> to be connected to emergency responses, or go to your nearest Hospital Emergency Room.
	                        </p>
                            <hr/>
	                        <h3>If you just want to talk:</h3>
	                        <p>
	                            Call the 24/7 VVCS - Veterans and Veterans Families Counselling Service on <a href="tel:1800-011-046">1800-011-046</a>. During business hours you will be transferred to the nearest VVCS office in your state.  After hours you will be connected with professional telephone counsellors at Veterans Line for immediate assistance, and you can opt to be connected to your local VVCS office for follow-up support.
	                        </p>
                            <hr/>
	                        <h3>To locate a mental health care professional:</h3>
	                        <p>
	                            The <a href="http://www.dva.gov.au/health_and_wellbeing/health_programs/vvcs/pages/index.aspx">VVCS - Veterans and Veterans Families Counselling Service (VVCS)</a> specialises in supporting Defence members, ex-serving members, veterans and their families with individual and group based treatment options. Call the  VVCS 24/7 on <a href="tel:1800-011-046">1800-011-046</a>.
	                        </p>
	                        <p>
	                        	To access a private mental health provider, your best place to start is with your GP, who can provide you with a referral to a psychiatrist, psychologist, or mental health social worker according to your need. 
	                        </p>
	                        <p>
	                           To find a psychologist you can also use the Australian Psychological Society's Find a Psychologist website here: 
	                            <a href="http://www.psychology.org.au/ReferralService/About/">http://www.psychology.org.au/ReferralService/About/</a>
	                        </p>
	                        <p>
	                            A list of mental health social workers can be found at <a href="http://www.aasw.asn.au/membersdirectory">http://www.aasw.asn.au/membersdirectory</a>.
	                        </p>
	                        <p>
								If hospitalisation is required, there are veteran specific mental health wards and treatment programs. To find out their location call DVA on 133 254 or 1800 555 254.
							</p>
	                        <p>
	                           If hospitalisation is required, there are veteran specific mental health wards and treatment programs. To find out their location call DVA on <a href="tel:133 254">133 254</a> or <a href="tel:1800555254">1800 555 254</a>.
							</p>
							<p>
								You also may wish to consider psychosocial and/or vocational rehabilitation services early on in your treatment. DVA can offer extensive rehabilitation services for entitled veterans  (<a href="http://www.dva.gov.au/rehabilitation">http://www.dva.gov.au/rehabilitation</a>).
							</p>
	                        ]]>
	                    </Content>
	                    <Content name="careForServing" predicate="dae.userType=='serving'">
	                        <![CDATA[
	                        <h2>Currently Serving Defence Members</h2>
	                        <p>
	                           ADF Joint Health Command is responsible for all healthcare services for ADF personnel including preparation for and support to deployed personnel. 
	                        </p>
                            <hr/>
	                        <h3>If you need immediate help:</h3>
	                        <p>
	                        	<a href="tel:1800467425">1800 IM SICK (1800 467 425)</a> )  is a national 24 hour call service providing world class nurse triage and health support for all ADF entitled personnel within Australia. 1800 IMSICK is NOT AN EMERGENCY NUMBER - in an emergency dial  <a href="tel:000">000</a>. 1800 IMSICK assists entitled ADF personnel to obtain health care, including mental health care if they become ill or injured afterhours and are not in close proximity to an On-Base health facility. 
	                        </p>
	                        <p>
	                           Your call will be answered by a registered nurse from Medibank Health Solutions who will assess your need for referral to your nearest facility or mental health provider.
	                        </p>
                            <hr/>
	                        <h3>If you just want to talk:</h3>
                            <p>
	                            Call the 24/7 VVCS - Veterans and Veterans Families Counselling Service on <a href="tel:1800-011-046">1800-011-046</a>. During business hours you will be transferred to the nearest VVCS office in your state.  After hours you will be connected with professional telephone counsellors at Veterans Line for immediate assistance, and you can opt to be connected to your local VVCS office for follow-up support.
                            </p>
	                        <p>
	                        	Alternatively, you can call the All-hours Support Line (ASL) on <a href="tel:1800628036">1800 628 036</a>. The ASL is a confidential telephone counselling support service for ADF personnel and their families that is available 24 hours a day, seven days a week.
	                        </p>
	                        <p>
	                        	Defence Family members can also call the <a href="http://www.defence.gov.au/dco">Defence Community Organisation</a>'s Family Helpline <a href="tel:1800624608">1800 624 608</a>, for a range of supports and programs for families and children of Defence members.
	                        </p>
                                <hr/>
	                        <h3>To locate a mental health care provider:</h3>
	                        <p>
	                            In Defence, mental health care professionals are available at your nearest Garrison Health Service, Mental Health and Psychology Section, or through a Medical Officer.
	                        </p>
	                        <p>
	                        	Defence members may be referred by their medical officer to VVCS, and eligible Defence members can also self-refer to <a href="http://www.dva.gov.au/health_and_wellbeing/health_programs/vvcs/pages/index.aspx">VVCS></a>.  VVCS specialises in supporting Defence members, Ex-Defence members and the families of veterans, and they  provide individual and group based treatment options. It is important that your Defence medical officer is aware that you are accessing services from VVCS. Call the 24/7 VVCS - Veterans and Veterans Families Counselling Service on <a href="tel:1800-011-046">1800-011-046</a>.
	                        </p>
                            <hr/>
	                        <h3>To locate a mental health care provider in the community:</h3>
	                            <p>
	                           If you do not have a Defence background, or would prefer to access a community service provider your best place to start is with your GP, who can provide you with a referral to a psychologist, mental health social worker or psychiatrist. 
	                            </p>
	                            <p>
	                            To find a psychologist you can also use the Australian Psychological Society's Find a Psychologist website here:
	                            <a href="http://www.psychology.org.au/ReferralService/About/">http://www.psychology.org.au/ReferralService/About/</a>
	                            </p>
	                            <p>
	                            A list of mental health trained social workers can be found at <a href="http://www.aasw.asn.au/membersdirectory">http://www.aasw.asn.au/membersdirectory</a>.
	                            </p>
	                            <p>
	                            If hospitalisation is required, there are veteran specific mental health wards and treatment programs. To find out their location call
	                            DVA on <a href="tel:133 254">133 254</a> or <a href="tel:1800555254">1800 555 254</a>.
	                            </p>
	                            <p>
	                            You also may wish to consider psychosocial and/or vocational rehabilitation services early on in your treatment. DVA can offer extensive rehabilitation
	                            services for entitled veterans (<a href="http://www.dva.gov.au/rehabilitation">http://www.dva.gov.au/rehabilitation</a>).
	                            </p>
	                        ]]>
	                    </Content>
	                    <Content name="careForUnknown" predicate="!dae.userType">
	                        <![CDATA[
	                            In order to help you find the right kind of care, please go to the Settings screen and tell me whether you are a currently serving defence member, or an ex-defence member.
	                        ]]>
	                        <Content name="@button" displayName="Go to Setup" ref="setup" refAction="pop"/>
	                    </Content>
	                </Content>
	            </Content>
	        </Content>
	        <Content ui="NavController" displayName="Schedule" icon="83-calendar.png" >
	        	<Content name="schedule" buttonTheme="theme_medium_button" ui="ButtonGridController" title="Schedule" backButton="Schedule"
	                buttongrid_cellsPerRow="1" buttongrid_buttonjust="left">
                    <Content name="@back" icon="home_icon.png" ref="home"/>
	                <Content name="scheduleAssessments" title="Schedule Assessments" displayName="Schedule Assessments" ui="PCLSchedulerController" icon="schedule_assessment.png">
	                    <![CDATA[Select a schedule to retake the self-assessment and monitor your progress. Taking the assessment monthly is ideal.]]>
	                    <Content name="none" displayName="Never"/>
	                    <Content name="week" displayName="Weekly"/>
	                    <Content name="twoweek" displayName="Every two weeks"/>
	                    <Content name="month" displayName="Monthly"/>
	                    <Content name="threemonth" displayName="Every three months"/>
	                </Content>
	                <Content name="scheduleTool" displayName="Reminder to use a Tool" title="Tool Reminder" ui="ScheduleToolController" icon="schedule_tool.png"><![CDATA[
                        Select a tool from the list below to schedule for use at a future time.
	                ]]></Content>
	                <Content name="scheduleActivity" displayName="Schedule Appointment or Activity" title="Schedule Appointment" ui="ScheduleAppointmentController" icon="schedule_appointment.png">
	                	Enter an event name and time for the appointment or activity you wish to schedule.
	                </Content>
	                <Content name="viewReminders" displayName="View Reminders" title="Reminders" ui="ReminderListController" icon="view_reminders.png"><![CDATA[
	                    These are all of the reminders you've set with PTSD Coach.  Reminders that are coming due will also be shown on the Home screen.
	                ]]></Content>
	            </Content>
	        </Content>
		</Content>
    </Content>

    <Content name="pickCalendar" ui="CalendarPickerController" title="Choose Calendar" settingKey="eventCalendar"><![CDATA[
        In order to schedule appointments that will show up in your device's calendar application, you'll' need to select a calendar to use below.  If you want to keep appointments and other
        PTSD Coach events private, make sure to use a private calendar (for example, don't use one that gets synchronized with a calendar related to your job).  If you like, you can
        create a new private calendar just for PTSD Coach events.
    ]]></Content>
    
	<Content name="crisis" ui="CrisisIntroController" displayName="Crisis" buttonTheme="theme_big_button">
		That's a very high distress level. It may be best for you to get some immediate support. Would you like to talk to someone now?
        <Content name="@next" displayName="Get Support Right Now" icon="support_now.png" ui="ContentViewController" title="Crisis Resources" theme="theme_default" standalone="1">
            <Content name="@inline">For any crisis, including medical emergencies:</Content>
            <Content name="@inline" ui="ContentListViewController">
                <Content displayName="Call 000" href="tel:000"/>
            </Content>
            <Content name="@inline"><![CDATA[Veterans and Veterans Families Counselling Service:]]></Content>
            <Content name="@inline" ui="ContentListViewController">
                <Content displayName="Call 1800-011-046" href="tel:1800-011-046"/>
            </Content>
            <Content name="@inline" predicate="dae.preferredContactSet">
                <Content name="@inline">Your preferred mental health professional:</Content>
                <Content name="@inline" ui="ChosenContactListViewController" show="preferredOnly"/>
            </Content>
            <Content name="@inline" predicate="(dae.contactsCount>0 &amp;&amp; !dae.preferredContactSet) || dae.contactsCount>1">
                <Content name="@inline">Your support contacts:</Content>
                <Content name="@inline" ui="ChosenContactListViewController" show="nonPreferredOnly"/>
            </Content>
            <Content name="@inline" predicate="(dae.contactsCount==0) || !dae.contactsCount">
                Your don't have any support contacts selected.  Visit 'Setup' to select your support contacts.
                <Content name="@button" displayName="Go to Setup" ref="setup" refAction="pop"/>
            </Content>
            <Content name="@button" displayName="Back to Manage" ref="manage"/>
        </Content>
	</Content>
	
	<Content name="changePerspectiveHelp" displayName="Change your Perspective"><![CDATA[
		The Change Your Perspective tools provide reminders that can help give you hope and confidence. We all have a constant stream of thoughts running through our minds—this is called self-talk.  Negative self-talk, like believing that things are terrible or that the worst is about to happen can stress your body and keep you on alert all the time. These positive self-talk reminders give you something you can hold on to; they can help you think more realistically, and may even help you manage situations more effectively.
		]]></Content>
	
	<Content name="groundingHelp" displayName="Grounding"><![CDATA[
		These exercises are simple strategies to help distract and detach from intense emotional distress, or, on the other hand, to help you reconnect to your body or self if you feel disconnected, numb, ‘foggy' or detached.  The grounding strategies in each section are geared specifically for the symptom you selected.
	]]></Content>

	<Content name="reduceIsolationHelp" displayName="Reduce Isolation"><![CDATA[
		These exercises are suggestions and strategies to help you reconnect with others. Often people who have been through trauma will prefer to be by themselves but at the same time may wish to be close to others again. But, being social may feel stressful or irritating, making it hard to reconnect with others.  Possibly, other people complain about your being distant even though you are not bothered by it. This may be because they care about you and would like to be closer to you. If your isolation is causing problems for your relationships or you want to feel more connected, these exercises and tips can help you begin to reconnect to the people in your life.
		]]></Content>
	
	<Content name="quotesHelp" displayName="Inspiring Quotes"><![CDATA[
		These quotes may offer inspiration and new perspectives for trauma survivors.
		]]></Content>

	<Content name="sootheHelp" displayName="Soothe Yourself"><![CDATA[
		These are activities to help you soothe yourself in the face of very upsetting or overwhelming emotions related to PTSD. Self-soothing involves 
		comforting and being kind to yourself. It may not make your feelings go away, but it can make handling them a little easier.
		]]></Content>
	
	<Content name="timeOutHelp" displayName="Take a Time Out"><![CDATA[
		This exercise allows you to take a break from a situation that is heating up before you (or someone else) do something you'll regret.  Time out is a time-limited break from a conflict (often 10-15 minutes) that helps people manage their anger so that they can resolve their conflicts more effectively. The time out exercise offers more instructions and guidance on how and when to take a time out, and what to do to help you cool down during your time out.	
		]]></Content>
	
	<Content name="sleepHelp" displayName="Fall Asleep"><![CDATA[
		These strategies include tips for falling asleep right now, as well as advice for managing insomnia so that you can fall asleep more easily on a regular basis. People who have experienced a trauma often have a hard time falling or staying asleep, or struggle with nightmares.  These strategies, along with some of the relaxation exercises in this app, can help you relax and sleep better.	
		]]></Content>
	
	<Content name="pleasantHelp" displayName="Pleasant Events"><![CDATA[
		This exercise will guide you in choosing and planning enjoyable activities in order to increase the amount of pleasure in your life. Especially if you're feeling down, it can be hard to get motivated to do the things that would usually be fun or give you a feeling of accomplishment. However, research shows that making an effort to do these things even when you don't feel like it can ultimately improve your mood.
		]]></Content>

	<Content name="seekSupportHelp" displayName="Seek Support"><![CDATA[
		This activity will guide you in reaching out for support. Reaching out for support can be difficult when you're feeling down or upset; however, having good support is strongly related to improved mood and mental health, and may be an important part of your recovery from trauma.		
		]]></Content>

	<Content name="distractHelp" displayName="Distract Yourself"><![CDATA[
		These are suggested activities to help you distract yourself from overwhelming emotions and the situations that may be triggering them. Distracting yourself may not completely make your feelings go away, but it can make surviving them a little easier.
		]]></Content>
	
	
	
	
</iStressLess>
